(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Doctor Who (1963) 11x01 The Time Warrior
(whopix fan edit version)
《神秘博士》老版第十一季第一集 《时间勇士》 (粉丝剪辑版)
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
基于opensubtitles.org 英文字幕翻译
(SPACESHIP WHIRRING)
Stars are falling!
星星都掉下来了！
It has fallen in the forest!
它掉到森林里面去了！
Come on, get up. Get up! Get up!
快来, 起来, 起来！起来！
It is an omen.
这是个征兆
- An evil sign! - It is mine.
- 这是个邪恶的符号！  - 它是我的
Irongron's star. I will have it!
是我 Irongron 的星星。我要拿到它！
- Hurry. Fetch the horses.
- Hurry? Hurry where?
- 快点, 牵马过来  - 快点？快点去哪儿？
To find the star before some knave robs me of it.
It landed close by.
去找星星, 免得一会儿被些混混给抢走了。它落在附近了
But the forest is still in darkness.
Who knows what demons may set upon us?
但森林还黑着呢, 谁知道会不会有恶魔在等着我们？
Why, you chicken-hearted knaves, every man of you!
啥？你们这些鼠胆, 你们所有人都是！
It's but an hour till dawn! Let's wait till then.
还有不到一小时就天亮了！ 我们等一会儿吧
To wait and see what faces us. We'll follow you then, Captain.
等一等再看那里有什么, 那时候我们会跟你去的, 头儿
Let all be made ready. I ride at dawn. - Alone if need be.
把一切都准备好, 天一亮我就要 —— 没人我就自己去
We're with you, Captain.
我们会跟着你的, 头儿
Then bring me some wine.
那再给我来点酒
We'll drink a toast to Irongron's star.
我们为 Irongron 的星星喝一杯
A star. A fallen star.
星星, 一颗坠落的星星
Careful, Captain, looks like the devil's work to me.
小心点, 头儿, 看起来像是魔鬼的杰作
A warrior? A warrior from the stars!
Have you come to challenge me?
一位勇士？从星星上来的勇士！你是来向我挑战的吗？
(HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING)
Flee for your life, Captain!
逃命要紧啊, 头儿！
- What creature is this?
- 'Tis a devil from hell.
- 这是什么怪物？   - 这是地狱来的魔鬼
Peace.
冷静
Fear not. I shall not harm you.
不用害怕, 我不会伤害你的
It speaks. Who are you? Where do you come from?
它会说话。你是谁？你从哪里来的？
I am a Sontaran officer.
我是一个桑塔军官
My name is Linx.
我的名字是 Linx
Help you? Why should I help you, star warrior?
帮你？为什么我要帮你, 星星勇士？
Why should I not kill you and take your ship
and its treasure for myself?
为什么我不杀了你, 抢走你的船和船里的宝贝呢？
LINX: The ship is in need of repair.
这艘船需要维修
Even if it were not, you would destroy
yourself should you tamper with it.
即使它不需要维修, 你去动它的话你同样会完蛋
Then why should I not just slay you for sport?
那要不然我就只宰掉你, 寻个开心？
Can you overcome all of us with your magic?
你能搞定我们所有人吗 — 用你的“魔法”？
LINX: You are a soldier, are you not? A warrior?
你是一个战士, 对不？一个勇士？
I took this castle by force of arms.
我凭着武力夺下了这座城堡
Those that were here before me, I slew.
之前这里的人, 都被我赶回去了
All the countryside around here pays my tribute.
周边的村子都要给我上贡
Yet no doubt you have enemies?
那你肯定有敌人吧？
Other warriors who envy your good fortune?
有一些勇士会嫉妒于你的好运？
Aye, but they cannot harm me.
是有, 不过他们伤害不了我
The king has levied tribute.
All their troops are at the wars.
国王四处征收, 他们的人也在四处忙着打仗
And when they return?
那他们回来之后呢？
Then we shall fight.
那我们就会战斗
I can give you weapons,
我可以给你武器
weapons that can make you masters,
so that none dare stand against you.
这些武器可以让你成为主人, 没人再敢站出来反对你
You shall take what castles you will.
你想要哪座城堡都没问题了
Magic weapons? Like that, that smote the sword from my hand?
魔法武器吗？ 就像那种...无形中击飞我的剑的那种？
Other weapons fitter for your purpose.
还有其它符合你需要的武器
Weapons that can strike a man dead from far away.
于远处夺人性命那种武器
- You can be supreme warrior.
- I can be king.
- 你就可以成为超级勇士了 - 我还可以成国王哩
But what do you ask in return, apart from your life?
但你需要什么作为回报呢, 除了饶你不死之外？
Shelter.
庇护
A place to conceal my ship and help with its repair.
需要一个地方把我的飞船藏起来, 还需要有人帮忙进行维修
- You have men that can work in metal?
- An armourer to sharpen weapons,
- 你有人会锻造金属不？ - 有个会打造武器的
a smith with a forge if these will serve your need.
有铁匠和熔炉, 应该能满足你的需要了
I need more, much more.
我需要很多, 非常多
There is damage to the drive mechanism of my ship.
我的飞船的驱动系统受损了
I need alloy, skilled technicians, complex circuitry.
我需要合金, 需要技工, 还有人对付复杂的电路
Oh, we have none of these things of which you speak.
哦, 你说的这些我们一样也没有
Then I must take them from those who have.
那我只能自己找了
In here, Brigadier?
是这里吗, 准将？
Yes, I'm afraid so, Doctor. Not exactly the Ritz, I know,
是的, 恐怕是这样, 博士。不是值得炫耀的地方, 我知道
but it's no joke providing emergency accommodation
for all these scientists.
但要给这么多科学家提供紧急住所, 也不是容易的事情
All right, Brigadier,
you've had your little bit of mystification.
好吧, 准将, 你已经完成了你的小奇迹
Now I know where I'm supposed to stay,
perhaps you wouldn't mind telling me why?
现在我知道我应该呆在哪里了。但或许你能告诉我这都是为什么？
This place is one of the most top secret
security establishments in the whole country.
这个地方是全国最绝密的安全机构之一
Most of their work is so secret,
这里的人所做的事情是如此机密
they don't know what they're doing themselves.
他们自己都不知道自己在做些什么
And?
怎么？
It's also one of the best-guarded places in the country.
这里也是全国安保措施最好的地方之一
Security details, alarm systems...
安全检查, 告警系统...
I rather gathered that when we arrived.
我们到这里的时候我都注意到了
For a moment I thought they weren't going to let you in.
有那么一会儿我以为他们连你都不允许进来了
Yes, exactly. The place is almost too security conscious.
是的, 的确如此, 这个地方似乎在安全上有点过于过分了
That's what makes it all the more puzzling.
但这就使得问题更加令人困惑了
Makes what all the more puzzling?
使得什么问题更令人困惑？
Come on, Brigadier, you can tell me.
好啦, 准将, 你可以跟我说的
- People vanishing.
- People?
- 有人消失  - 有人？
Well, they've lost. Half a dozen leading scientists
是的, 他们不见了。半打顶尖科学家
and several million pounds' worth of ultra-secret equipment.
还有几百万英镑的超级机密设备
What are they working on here anyway?
他们到底在这里是研究什么的？
Space hardware. New alloys, guidance systems,
methods of propulsion.
太空材料、新型合金、导航系统、太空推进器等
- And what action have you taken so far?
- Well, I had rather a bright idea.
- 目前位置你都采取了什么措施没有？  - 哦, 我有一个不错的想法
It's pretty hard to keep an eye
on all these scientist chaps at home,
如果让这些科学家呆在家里, 我们很难全部盯住他们
so I had these cubicles put up on several floors.
所以我让人在这几层搭了这些小格间
Confined the whole lot to barracks,
all my eggs in one basket so to speak.
把这些人都圈到这里, 简单地说, 所有的鸡蛋都到一个篮子了
That's fine, so long as no one steals the basket.
这不错啊——如果没人能偷走这个篮子的话
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Linx! My Lord Linx!
Linx！Linx 大人!
Will you open the door?
你能打开门吗？
LINX: None may enter here.
Such was my agreement with your captain.
没人可以进来。这是我跟你们头领达成的协议
Yay, it is my captain who sent me.
知道, 但正是我们头儿派我来的
He would have words with you, Lord Linx.
他想跟你谈谈, Linx 大人
Then tell him I'm occupied. Now leave me to my work.
那告诉他我没空, 别打扰我工作
(BANGS ON DOOR)
Insolent primitives. Did I not need their aid...
无礼的原始人。我干脆不要他们帮忙算了...
Where is the star warrior?
星星勇士在哪儿？
He would not come. He says he's occupied.
他不肯来, 他说他正忙
Oh, the insolent barbarian.
Did I not need his help, I'd...
噢, 无礼的野蛮人。我不要他的帮助, 我要...
See, Bloodaxe. The first of the new weapons.
你看, Bloodaxe, 第一批新武器
Watch!
看着！
Oh! Claps the ears!
噢, 捂住耳朵！
I'll soon master the aim.
我很快就能瞄得准了
Rubeish.
- I beg your pardon?
- Joseph Rubeish.
- 对不起没听清 - 我叫Joseph Rubeish
Oh, I see. I'm so sorry. Hello. How do you do?
哦, 明白了, 对不起。嗨, 你好
It's disgraceful, of course. Utterly disgraceful.
这太不恰当了, 的确, 非常不恰当
Oh? What is?
噢？什么？
Well, shutting us up. Like a lot of kids kept in after school.
不让我们说话, 就好像我们放学后被留住的小孩子似的
And that brigadier chap, military idiot.
就那个准将, 没脑子的军人
Yes, I know how you feel. Still, he means well, you know.
是的, 我知道你的感受。不过, 他本意是好的, 你也知道
Haven't seen my wife and family for three days.
我都三天没见过我的老婆和家人了
I'm sorry to hear that.
很抱歉听到这个
Ah, well, just shows there's always a silver lining.
啊, 好吧, 还算是有一线希望
- And your name?
- Uh, Smith, Dr John Smith.
- 你的名字是？ - 噢, 史密斯, 约翰-史密斯博士
- Seems to be a lot of them about today.
- I'm sorry?
- 今天这里好像有好多史密斯  - 什么？
I was talking to a young woman just now, also Smith.
我刚才还跟一个年轻女人说话, 也叫史密斯
- Well, there she is. Miss Smith?
- Yes, Professor?
- 喏, 她来了。史密斯小姐？  - 什么事, 教授？
Come and meet your namesake.
过来见见你的本家
- Miss Lavinia Smith, Doctor, uh...
- Dr John Smith.
- 我是 Lavinia Smith, 你是。。  - 约翰-史密斯博士
- How do you do, Miss Smith?
- Hello.
- 你好, 史密斯小姐  - 你好
Doctor, I'm intrigued. What's that for?
博士, 我很好奇, 那是做什么用的？
That? Oh, that, that contains my equipment, Professor.
那个, 哦, 那个是用来装我的设备的, 教授
That's original.
这倒没见过
- You're the virologist, Miss Smith?
- Yes.
- 你是个病毒学家, 史密斯小姐？ - 是的
Who told you?
谁告诉你的？
I read your paper on the teleological response of the virus,
我读过你那篇关于病毒的远程响应(??)方面的论文
- a most impressive piece of work.
- Thank you.
- 令人非常印象深刻 - 谢谢你
Particularly when I realised,
you must have written it when you were five years old.
尤其是我意识到, 你写那篇论文的时候应该才五岁
Ah, uh... Yes, that is rather difficult to explain, isn't it?
啊, 喔...是的, 这的确很难解释, 是吧
You're going to try, aren't you?
你不尝试解释一下吗？
Well, um... My Aunt Lavinia is in America
on a lecture tour, you see.
是这样, 唔...我的姨妈 Lavinia 因为要搞一个讲座去美国了, 明白吗
- Mmm-hmm.
- She had an invitation to visit here.
- 嗯哼  - 她有这里的邀请函
- I took her place.
- Why?
- 于是我就来了  - 为什么？
I thought all this might give me a good story.
我觉得这些会让我得到一个好故事
I'm a journalist. Sarah Jane Smith.
我是个新闻记者, 莎拉-简-史密斯
You realise this is a very dangerous place to be in?
你应该知道你呆的这个地方是非常危险的吧？
Well, I can't help that. I'm stuck here now.
只是, 我忍不住。不过现在被困住了
Anyway, we've got all these soldiers looking after us.
不管怎样, 我们还有这么些士兵保护着我们呢
Are you going to give me away, Doctor?
你会告发我吗, 博士？
- I don't think so.
- Why not?
- 我没这么想   - 为什么呢？
Well, you can make yourself useful.
嗯, 也许你能派上点用场
We need somebody around here to make the coffee.
我们这里需要有人泡个咖啡什么的
If you think I'm going to spend my time
making cups of coffee for you...
如果你觉得我会浪费我的时间来给你们泡咖啡的话...
Professor!
教授！
Would you kindly desist? This is not a blackboard, you know.
你能否好心放过它, 它并不是一块黑板, 你知道吧
Oh, I do beg your pardon, Doctor. I was just trying to prove...
哦, 请你原谅, 博士, 我只是想证明...
What are you going to do in there?
你打算在那里面做什么呢？
Make myself a cup of coffee. Good day to you.
给我自己泡一杯咖啡。祝你今天过得愉快
We caught this little rabbit in the forest, sire.
我们在林子里抓到了这个小兔子, 大人
Sir Edward's squire.
爱德华爵士的小跟班
- Are you loyal to your lord, boy?
- I am.
- 你对你家大人忠诚吗, 孩子？ - 是的
We shall see.
我们来看看
He carried this. He tried to eat it when we caught him.
他带着这个。我们抓到他的时候他想吞了它
Are Sir Edward's men so ill-fed?
爱德华爵士的人都这么面黄肌瘦的吗？
Bah! I make nothing of their Norman scribbles.
啊！我认不出这些诺曼人潦草的字迹
- What's it say?
- I cannot read, Captain.
- 上面说什么  - 我不识字, 头儿
What's the message say, boy?
这信里说什么, 孩子？
So your Sir Edward is going to attack me, eh?
这么说你家爱德华爵士打算来攻打我, 是不？
Well, speak.
怎样, 说话
I know nothing.
我什么也不知道
Take him below. We'll loosen his tongue presently.
带他下去。我们很快就能撬开他的舌头
- Edward.
- What is it? Is Eric back?
- 爱德华  - 什么事, Eric 回来了吗？
- You haven't eaten all day.
- Why does he not return?
- 你一整天都没有吃东西了  - 为什么他还没有回来？
I could have ridden to my Lord
of Salisbury's castle three times over.
这时间都够跑索尔兹伯里城堡三个来回了
- It's not good for you to worry so much.
- How can I not worry?
- 你这么担忧并没有什么好处  - 我怎么才能不担忧呢？
Think that tomorrow will be brighter.
想想明天会更好
Edward, I've heard that Irongron
walks his battlements every morning.
爱德华, 我听说 Irongron 每天早上都练兵
Oh, it pleases him to be high. He's like a cockerel.
哦, 他就喜欢那样, 像个好斗的小公鸡
But does he climb so high that an arrow cannot reach him?
但他爬得太高了, 箭都射不到?
LINX: Irongron.
(IRONGRON CHUCKLING)
That strange armour you wear suits you, Linx.
你这身奇怪的盔甲倒是很适合你, Linx
- It is Sontaran space armour.
- But why must we never see your face?
- 这是桑塔人的太空服  - 不过为什么我们从来没见过你的面容？
This helmet conceals the fact
that I am not of your kind, Irongron.
这个头盔已经说明了, 我跟你们不是同一个种族, Irongron
You might not find my true appearance pleasing.
你可能会发现我的真实面貌并不会令你愉悦
(CHUCKLING) By my sword, Linx,
I'll wage you're the fairest beauty in the castle.
以我的剑作见证, Linx, 我得说你是这座城堡最漂亮的
Why did you summon me? You know my work is pressing.
你为什么叫我来？你知道我的工作很紧
I have a prisoner in the dungeon,
a surly fellow who will not speak.
我的地牢里有个囚犯, 他死活不肯开口
- And you wish him to?
- Yes.
- 那你希望他开口？  - 是的
Then give him to me. I will make him speak.
那把他交给我吧, 我会让他说话的
Tell Bloodaxe to bring up the prisoner.
告诉 Bloodaxe 把囚犯带上来
Well, Linx, you cunning old devil,
好了, Linx, 你这狡猾的老魔鬼,
what fresh tricks can you show Irongron, eh?
有什么新花招展示给 Irongron 呢？
What is the nature of the information you seek?
你想要获得哪方面的信息？
He's a messenger of those who plot a war against me.
有人正在谋划一场反对我的战争, 他就是给他们传信的
A war? That is excellent.
一场战争？那太好了
- Oh, so you like war, eh?
- Who does not?
- 噢, 看来你喜欢战争, 啊？  - 谁不喜欢呢？
My race has been at war for millennia.
我的族人已经打了近千年的仗了
There is not a galaxy in the universe
which our space fleets have not subjugated.
这个宇宙里没有一个星系, 未被我们的太空舰队征服过
But you do not understand me.
但你听不懂我在说什么
I am stranded on this primitive planet
我被困在这个原始的星球上
when I should be leading my squadron to glory.
而我原本应该带着我的小分队迈向光荣
- I am an expert at war, Irongron.
- I know.
- 我是战争方面的专家, Irongron  - 我知道
What about those weapons you promised me?
你许诺给我的武器怎么样了？
Keep your side of the bargain, I shall keep mine.
你兑现你那一方的承诺, 我也兑现我的
You shall have your weapons.
你会得到你想要的武器
(GROWLING)
We make good allies, Linx.
Each has much that the other wants.
我们的联盟很不错, Linx, 每一边都有对方想要的东西
- Miss Smith...
- No, no, I'm the Doctor.
- 史密斯小姐  - 不, 不, 我是博士
You really must keep your glasses
on the end of your nose, Professor.
你真的要把你的眼镜固定在你的鼻子上, 教授
No, no. Listen, she's not Miss Smith.
不, 不, 听着, 她不是史密斯小姐
- She isn't?
- No. Who is she?
- 她不是？ - 不是, 她是谁？
I don't think I quite understand
what you're talking about, Professor.
我觉得我没太搞明白你在说什么, 教授
Just now I was in the common room with Sir Maxwell Dingle.
刚才我跟 Maxwell Dingle 爵士在客厅
I happened to mention I was on the same landing
with Lavinia Smith, the virologist.
我无意中提起我跟病毒学家 Lavinia Smith 住在一起
- And do you know what he says?
- Yes. He said that she's in America.
- 你知道他说什么？  - 知道, 他说她现在正在美国呢
He said she's in... How could you know?
他说她现在在...你怎么知道的？
Please be careful! This is very delicate equipment.
小心一点！这是非常精巧的设备
What if she's a spy? What do we do?
如果她是一个间谍怎么办？我们该做什么？
- Shoot her?
- Ha! There's something odd about her.
- 枪杀她？ - 哈, 她是有点奇怪
She even tried to tell me you were a spy.
她还试着跟我说过, 说你是个间谍
Am I on the right floor?
我没走错楼层吧？
- Good night.
- Good night, Professor.
- 晚安  - 晚安, 教授
- What's that?
- That's my alarm clock.
- 那是什么？  - 那是我的告警钟
Oh, Doctor, kindly don't be so patronising.
Now, what is it really?
哦, 博士, 不要这么拒人千里嘛。说真的, 这是什么？
It's a rhondium sensor. It detects delta particles.
这是一个铑探测器, 它可以检测到德尔塔粒子
Why do you want to be woken up
when it detects delta particles?
为什么你想要它检测到德尔塔粒子就向你告警
Because I am very fond of delta particles.
因为我非常喜欢德尔塔粒子
- Why do you ask so many questions?
- Because I'm a journalist.
- 为什么你要问这么多问题  - 因为我是个新闻记者
- Are you going to sleep there?
- If you'll allow me to do so.
- 那你打算睡在那里吗？  - 如果你允许的话
Good night, Miss Smith.
晚安, 史密斯小姐
He has a stout heart, this one, sire. He speaks not a word.
他骨头还挺硬啊, 大人。一个字也不说
Good. A fair measure for you, Linx.
好, 就看你的了, Linx
(HUMMING)
Well, come on, Linx, have at him!
嘿, 快啊, Linx, 对付他！
- Ask what you wish.
- Eh?
- 想问什么就问吧  - 嗯？
But you've done nothing.
你什么也没干啊
This is a key. I have unlocked your prisoner's mind.
这是一把钥匙, 我已经解开了这个囚徒的大脑
Question him.
问吧
How many men guard Sir Edward's castle?
爱德华爵士的城堡有多少人守卫？
There are but 10, old men for the most part.
只有不到10个人, 其中大部分还是老人
And he plans to attack me with 10 old men?
那他就打算用这10个老人来攻打我？
He sends messages to raise a force against you.
他送信让召集人马来对付你
If he succeed, then he will attack.
如果他成功了, 就会发起攻击
(IRONGRON LAUGHING)
Listen to the fellow! He cannot stop babbling.
听听这个家伙！他还真是能巴巴
Stay, Linx! Have I given you leave?
别走, Linx! 我说过让你走了吗？
Each of us has work to do, Irongron. I will be back.
我们都还有事情要做, Irongron, 我得回去了
(SNORING)
(PULSING)
Rubeish?
- Rubeish!
- What? Who is it?
- Rubeish! - 什么事？谁啊？
Oh, it's all right. Nothing to worry about. Just checking.
哦, 没事了。没什么可担心的, 我只是检查一下
- What's happening?
- You're asking questions again.
- 怎么了？ - 你又有问题要问了
(PULSE ACCELERATING)
(CRASHING)
- Professor Rubeish?
- Rubeish!
- Rubeish 教授?  - Rubeish!
- He's gone!
- Yes.
- 他不见了 - 是的
He was here a moment ago.
一秒钟以前他还在这里呢
He can't have gone far.
他应该不会走远
He's as blind as a bat without his glasses.
不带眼镜的话, 他会跟蝙蝠一样瞎
You stay here, Miss Smith. I'm going to check the landing.
你呆在这里, 史密斯小姐。我去检查一下楼层入口
- Anybody come out of here just now?
- No.
- 刚才有谁从这里出来吗？  - 没有
(BEEPING)
(BEEPING ACCELERATING)
- What were they shooting at?
- Shadows.
- 他们在朝什么开枪呢？ - 影子
Oh, come on, Doctor, stop treating me like a child.
哦, 得了, 博士, 别当我是小孩子
I can't understand why the definition was so low.
我不明白清晰度为什么这么低
Unless he's operating with a very weak
power source at maximum range.
除非他电力不足, 同时又将功率开到了最大
- Yes, of course.
- BRIGADIER: Doctor?
- 是了, 肯定是  - 博士？
- Doctor?
- Hello!
- 博士？  - 哈喽
Look, Doctor, we've had a raid.
Is everyone present on this landing?
看, 博士, 我们刚搞了一趟搜捕。这层楼每个人都还在吗？
No. Professor Rubeish is missing.
不, Rubeish 教授不见了
Oh, my giddy aunt! The Minister will go spare.
哦, 我滴个婶婶！部长又要发飙了
Did you see anything, Doctor?
你看到什么了吗, 博士？
- Yes.
- What?
- 是的 - 什么？
Well, I thought I saw a man in armour.
哦, 我想我看到一个穿着盔甲的人
- A man in armour?
- Mmm-hmm.
- 穿盔甲的人 - 嗯哼
You mean old-fashioned armour? You mean a ghost?
你是说老式盔甲？一个鬼魂？
Oh, I very much doubt it.
哦, 对此我很怀疑
- Sorry I can't stop, Brigadier.
- Why? Where are you going?
- 抱歉我不能耽搁了, 准将  - 为什么？你要去哪儿？
Well, I've got to get on the trail while it's still warm.
我要去追踪痕迹, 趁它还没有消失
What trail? The chap's just vanished.
什么痕迹？那个家伙已经消失了
No, he hasn't. I just got a fix on him.
不, 他还没有, 我已经锁定住他了
There's something very odd indeed going on.
不过的确有一些奇怪的事情
Yes. Well, if I may say so, Doctor,
that is not exactly news to me.
是啊, 让我说的话, 这对我也不是新闻了
(WHOOSHING)
Well done, old girl. Absolutely on target.
做得好, 老丫头。完全跟住目标了
For once.
总算有一次
It's still only a police box.
但这只是一个警察亭啊
I must find a telephone.
我得找到一个电话
Sir Edward only has a puny force. He stands within his walls.
爱德华爵士的人力少得可怜, 只能龟缩在他的城墙里
If we can only breach them, Bloodaxe.
如果我们能渗透进去, Bloodaxe
We could cut Sir Edward's soldiers down
in less time than our rogues spend with their breakfasts.
我们就能砍倒他那些士兵, 快得比我们的伙计吃早饭的时间还少
It's those accursed walls, walls like these.
那些令人憎恨的城墙, 像这样的墙
But with Linx's new weapons...
只要有了 Linx 的新武器
Excuse me, could you tell me where the nearest telephone...
打扰一下, 你能告诉我最近的电话机在哪里...
He flees through the forest. Take him!
他逃到森林里去了, 抓住他！
After him, you dogs! Through the forest!
去抓他, 你们这些！往林子里去了！
Oh, it must be some sort of pageant. I say...
哦, 肯定是某种露天表演, 我说...
Hey, you there. Hey, what are you doing? Get off!
嘿, 停下, 嘿, 你要干什么？放开我
- Let go of me! Hey!
- How the blazes did she get here?
- 放开我, 嘿！  - 她怎么跑到这里来了
SARAH: Stop it!
停下！
Look, if this is a rag day joke, it's not funny!
嘿, 如果这是什么节日玩笑, 太过了啊！
- Come on!
- Let me go! I won't tell you...
- 来吧！  - 放开我！我不会告诉你...
(TWIG SNAPS)
I won't tell you again!
我不会跟你说第二遍!
Look, I'm not amused. Stop it!
听着, 这并不好玩, 停下！
(TWIG SNAPS)
Come on.
进来吧
(GRUNTING)
Make it keen.
要磨锋利
I want Sir Edward not to know the moment
when his head is parted from...
我期望爱德华爵士的头被砍下来的时候他还没有反应过来...
(SHOUTING)
- What's this!
- She was found within bowshot, Captain.
- 这是什么？  - 在弓箭射程之内找到的, 头儿
Idiots! Why don't you stop this ridiculous pantomime?
蠢人！你们就不能停止你们这荒谬的表演吗？
She spits fire, eh, Bloodaxe? Come here, girl.
她会吐火啊, 是不, Bloodaxe? 过来, 女孩
Get lost! Oh! Ow!
消失！哦, 噢！
- She wears gold, Bloodaxe.
- That hurt, you fool!
- 她戴着金首饰, Bloodaxe  - 弄疼我了, 你这蠢人！
You call Irongron a fool?
你管 Irongron 叫蠢人?
I'll have the marrow from your bones, my little chicken.
我要把你的骨髓碾出来, 我的小鸡
Where are you from?
你从哪里来的？
Look, just pack this up, will you? It's not funny.
行了, 收起这些吧, 行吗？这并不有趣
I happen to be a reporter, and I've got a big story...
我恰好是个记者, 我还有个大事件要...
Take her away, Bloodaxe. Throw her in the dungeon.
把他带走, Bloodaxe。扔到地牢里去
Why don't you take off that ridiculous gear
and go home to your butcher's shop?
你们为什么不脱掉你们那可笑的行头, 回到你们的肉铺去呢？
Let go! Look, I warn you.
放开！嘿, 我警告你
Any more of this and I'm going straight to the police.
再这样我就直接报警了啊
- Stay, Bloodaxe!
- Captain?
- 停下, Bloodaxe！  - 头儿？
Leave her.
放开她
That's better.
这还差不多
(SCOFFS) Now, if I could just use your telephone.
现在, 我能否用一下你们的电话
(MAN GROANING)
This is the dog that shot at you, Captain!
就是这条狗朝你射箭的, 头儿！
So you thought to kill Irongron, eh?
看来你是想杀 Irongron, 嗯？
Aye, and I would but for her. She drew my aim aside.
是, 要不是她我就成功了。她干扰了我
You treacherous dog!
你这奸诈的小狗！
- Did Sir Edward send you?
- No.
- 是爱德华爵士派你来的吗？  - 不是
- You lie!
- I speak the truth!
- 你撒谎！  - 我说的是事实！
- If not Sir Edward, who then?
- I don't understand. Where am I?
- 如果不是爱德华爵士, 那是谁？  - 我搞不懂了, 我在哪儿？
It was my Lady Eleanor.
是我家夫人 Eleanor
Ah, that narrow-hipped vixen.
啊, 那个小心眼的泼妇
Bloodaxe, tomorrow we dine at Wessex Castle.
Bloodaxe, 明天我们就到 Wessex 城堡去吃晚饭
Yes, Captain. And what of the prisoner?
好, 头儿！这个囚犯怎么处理？
Ere long we shall deal with him sharply.
稍后我们再来严厉处置他
(LAUGHING)
Sharply, eh? 'Tis richly put.
严厉地, 嗯？这词用得好吧
Aye. That'll be a fine jest, Captain Irongron.
啊, 那是个不错的词, Irongron 队长
I'm not one of your stuffy Norman nobles.
我可不是你们那些自以为是的诺曼贵族
I like a bit of rough fun.
我喜欢玩点野蛮趣味
'Tis true, Captain, you have a merry wit indeed!
这是真的, 头儿, 你真是个有头脑的人！
Look, please! Now you've had your laugh,
请, 听着！既然你们笑也笑了,
now, you know, just let's stop it and talk sensibly.
现在, 你看, 我们停下来认真地谈一谈
I mean, if it's any consolation to you,
you're scaring me out of my wits.
我是说, 如果你们觉得这些很好玩, 但我真的被吓破胆子了
- Perhaps the wench is crazed, Captain.
- Oh, come on. What is this place?
- 好像这个村姑被吓傻了, 头儿  - 噢, 得了, 这是什么地方？
You are in the castle of Irongron, my lady.
你在 Irongron 的城堡里, 我的夫人
Few uninvited guests come here,
and few that do leave alive.
很少有人不请自来, 更少人能活着离开
All right. If you insist on playing guessing games...
好吧, 如果你们非要玩这种猜谜游戏...
Now, it's not a village pageant.
It's too elaborate for that.
现在, 这不是一个村庄表演, 因为这太复杂了
A film set. No, no lights, no cameras.
电影拍摄现场。不, 没有灯, 也没有摄像机
Aye, the wench is crazed, right enough.
And pity, she's not un-comely.
是, 这村姑吓傻了, 肯定的。可惜了, 她本来还不难看
I've got it! It's one of those tourist places.
我知道了！这是一个旅游观光点
Uh, a medieval castle,
all restored to its original condition
喔, 一个中世纪城堡, 所有都恢复到原样
with jolly banquets and buxom serving wenches.
带着欢乐宴席, 活泼的女仆
That's it, isn't it?
就是这样, 对不对？
Mind you, I think you're overdoing the sordid realism a bit.
提醒一下,你们把脏乱这一点做得过头了
I mean, I know things were pretty grotty in the Middle Ages,
我是说, 我知道中世纪的时候很多东西是不怎么样
but, really, you might leave the tourists
a bit of glamorous illusion.
但, 真的, 你们应该给游客留下一个好的印象
I've never seen such a scurvy...
我从来没有见过这么无礼地...
For pity's sake, cease this babbling, girl!
天可怜见, 别叨叨了, 女孩儿！
BLOODAXE: Captain.
头儿
Ah, Linx. What of my weapons? Are they ready?
啊, Linx, 我的武器怎样了？准备好了吗？
Soon. But I have another weapon to show you.
快了。但我要给你展示另外一样武器
- For your leave, master, the prisoner?
- Aye, aye.
- 那就留给你了, 主人, 那个囚犯？  - 好, 好
- What is this?
- Eh?
- 这是什么？  - 嗯？
- Oh, just a girl taken in the forest.
- Girl?
- 哦, 只是一个女孩儿, 森林里面抓到的  - 女孩儿？
- You have two species on this planet?
- How say you?
- 你们这个星球有两个物种吗？  - 怎么说？
The girl is not of your kind, Irongron.
这个女孩跟你不是一个类别, Irongron
The hair is finer. The thorax of a different construction.
头发要好一些, 胸膛的结构也不太一样
Oh, hell's teeth, have you no girls beyond the stars?
哦, 可怜呐, 你们那星星上没有女孩儿？
- No women to do the lowly work?
- Ah, I understand.
- 没有人做一些低等的活儿？  - 啊, 我明白了
You have a primary and secondary reproductive cycle.
你们有一个高等和低等的生殖循环
It is an inefficient system. You should change it.
这个系统很没效率, 你们应该改掉它
You what?
你说什么？
In the Sontaran Military Academy,
在桑塔军事学院
we have hatchings of a million cadets at each muster parade.
我们每次集结时, 都生成上百万的士官生
Thus we can sustain enormous casualties on all battlefronts.
所以我们能承受那么多战线上的巨大伤亡
You cluck away like a broody old hen.
你们的方法好像多产的老母鸡啊
Wait! This cloth is machine-woven.
等一下, 这个衣服是机器造出来的
The girl is not of your time, Irongron.
这个女孩儿不是你们这个时代的, Irongron
Oh, curse the girl! Show me the...
啊, 该死的女孩！向我说明...
Who? What? How?
谁？ 什么？ 什么情况？
Sarah Jane Smith. Reporter.
莎拉-简-史密斯, 记者
In a machine. I did not understand it.
在一个机器里, 我搞不明白它
- What century?
- Twentieth.
- 哪个世纪？  - 二十
Your civilisation knows nothing
of time-dimensional technology. Explain.
你们的文明没有时间维度技术方面的知识。解释
I cannot. It is a machine that
belongs to someone called the Doctor.
我解释不了, 那个机器属于某个叫做博士的人
- Linx...
- Silence!
- Linx...  - 安静!
This is important. My mission is threatened.
这很重要, 我的任务有威胁了
Explain the Doctor.
解释一下“博士”
He is a scientist. He was at the research centre.
他是个科学家, 他当时在研究中心
He said he was very fond of delta particles.
他说他非常喜欢德尔塔粒子
Ah. Is he here?
啊, 他现在在这里吗？
Yes. Somewhere. I was hiding in the machine when he left.
是的, 在某个地方。他出来的时候我还躲在机器里
It becomes clear.
事情清楚了
Linx, what of the weapon?
Linx, 武器的事情怎样了？
Very well.
很好
It is here.
来了
Who are you? How do you come into my castle?
你是谁？你怎么到我的城堡里来的？
Well, speak fellow!
喂, 说话伙计！
Answer me or lose your head for insolence!
回答我, 否则你的头就没了, 无礼的家伙！
It cannot answer you.
It is just a suit of steel. It is empty.
它没法回答你。它只是一堆铁片, 里面是空的
But it walks!
但他能走路啊
It walks. And it fights, Irongron. Is it a good weapon?
它能走路, 还能战斗, Irongron。这个武器还不错吧？
Does it kill?
它能杀人吗？
It does nothing else and it cannot be killed.
它就会干这个, 而且还不会被杀
By heavens, Linx, can you make me more of these?
天啊, Linx, 你能给我多造几个这个吗？
If you wish.
只要你想要
With a few such soldiers as that, I could take the world!
只要有几个这样的士兵, 我能夺下整个世界！
When I have left this dull planet,
当我离开这个无趣的星球时
it would amuse me to think of it
under the rule of King Irongron.
想到它是在 Irongron 国王的统治之下, 还是会觉得有点意思的
Very well, provide me with all that I ask for
很好, 只要把我说的东西都提供过来
- and I can make many more of these.
- It's a bargain.
- 我就能找出更多这个来  - 说定了
By heavens, Linx, I never thought when I first saw you
老天, Linx, 我第一次看见你的时候, 我从没想到
that I should come to love you as a brother.
有一天我会像一个兄弟一样爱你
Now, show me how the iron man works.
现在, 给我展示一下铁人是怎么用的
Wait. The girl creature has gone.
等一下。那个女孩生物跑掉了
Oh, she'll not get far before one of my guards grabs her tail.
哦, 她跑不了多远就会被我的守卫给抓回来
Now, show me. Show me how it fights. Make it walk again.
来, 展示一下, 展示一下它是怎么战斗的, 让它再走起来
Sarah? Miss Smith. Come back!
莎拉？史密斯小姐。回来！
- Stay! Bloodaxe.
- Sire.
- 停下, Bloodaxe  - 大人
- Would you fight for your life, fellow?
- I'll fight any man, my lord.
- 你愿意为你的性命战斗吗, 伙计？  - 我愿意跟任何人打, 大人
(IRONGRON LAUGHING)
- Then stand against Irongron's champion.
- Who is this?
- 那就来跟我的护卫打吧  - 这是谁？
You'll see some sport now, Bloodaxe. Here, fellow.
你也消遣一下, Bloodaxe。来吧, 伙计
Master, this is not fair combat
to pitch knight against bowman.
主人, 让骑士直接对战弓箭手是不公平
At this close range, his arrows'll
pierce the armour's weak points.
在这么近的距离下, 他的箭会刺穿盔甲的薄弱之处
- Take aim, fellow.
- I am that.
- 瞄准, 伙计  - 我瞄好了
Your freedom if you kill him. Stand back.
你能否自由就看你能否杀了他了。往后退
Your champion'll have more arrows
in his gizzard than a thistle has spikes.
你的护卫身上中的箭可要比刺猬的刺还多了
My lord, look! He still moves!
大人，快看！他还能动！
(MEN LAUGHING)
What fool...
哪个傻瓜...
Guard your back, my lord!
注意你后面，大人！
BLOODAXE: Captain!
头儿！
Psst!
噗斯
By heavens, Bloodaxe, 'tis like a tin tadpole.
老天，Bloodaxe，这家伙就像个蝌蚪似的
You cut off its head and yet it wriggles.
砍掉它的脑袋，它还能扭动
I'll have a word with Linx about this.
我得跟 Linx 说说这个情况
(GROWLING)
(MEN LAUGHING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
IRONGRON: Linx? Linx, you mongrel!
Linx? Linx 你个杂种
I have a bone to pick with you. Come here!
我得跟你理论理论，过来！
I am occupied, Irongron.
我正忙，Irongron
What! Out this minute or I'll burst the door down.
什么？过了这会儿我可就把门砸碎了啊
Well? What is it you need to say to me?
怎么？你有什么要同我说的？
Didn't I tell you you might not find my face pleasing?
我有没有告诉过你，你可能会不太喜欢我的相貌
Aye, and never was truer word spoken.
是，再也没有比这更实在的话了
Are they all so fair of face beyond the stars?
星星上面的人都是这样的相貌吗
The variety of sentient life forms is infinite.
智慧生命的形式是无限的
Do you think your primitive features are pleasing to me?
就你们这原始生命的相貌，你觉得我会喜欢吗？
-Well, what is it you want?
-That accursed iron warrior of yours.
- 好了，你想要什么 - 你那个下了咒语的铁武士
You are pleased with it?
你还满意吗？
Some knave with a crossbow shot the control from my hand.
某个拿十字弓的混蛋从我手上把控制器射掉了
The iron man became crazed, tried to kill all of us.
那个铁人就疯了，要杀了我们所有人
Perhaps the hand control unit itself is a weakness.
也许手持控制器本身就是个弱点
I will make you a better warrior, Irongron.
我会给你造一个更好的武士，Irongron
One that'll obey your voice perhaps.
一个服从你的声音的，或许
First, help me kill the one I have now.
It still struggles to slay my knaves.
首先，帮我杀了我已经有的那个，它还在追杀我的那些混球呢
It cannot be killed. It was never alive.
不可能杀死它，它从来也不是活的
Come, I will de-activate it.
来，我来关闭它
Professor Morrison?
莫瑞森教授？
Professor.
教授
Absolute lunacy.
完全精神错乱了
- Rubeish!
- What? Who is it?
- Rubeish！- 啥？谁啊？
It's me. It's the Doctor. Don't you remember?
是我，博士。还记得我吗
We were on the same landing at the research centre.
在研究中心时我们在同一楼层啊
Oh, my dear fellow. So he's got you, too, has he?
噢，亲爱的朋友，这么说他把你也抓住了，是吗？
No, hardly. Look, Professor,
what's wrong with all these people?
不，没那么容易。看看，教授，这些人是怎么回事？
Hypnotised. Can't get a word out of them. Rotten company.
都被催眠了，从他们那里一个字也问不出来。都烂掉了
- Well, you seem to be all right.
- Oh, didn't work with me.
- 不过，你好像挺正常 - 哦，对我不起作用
- Strong-minded, you see.
- Yes, and very nearly blind.
- 意志力很强的，你看  - 是的，而且很盲
Oh, nonsense.
噢，胡说
Obviously working some sort of ocular device.
显然是某种视觉屏蔽装置
Professor, have you any idea where you are?
教授，对于你现在在哪儿你有概念吗？
Some medieval English castle, I suspect.
某座中世纪英国城堡吧，我怀疑
I've been feeling the carvings on some of these columns.
我是从这些柱子上的雕刻来揣测的
They're astonishingly well preserved.
它们保存得异常地完好
Yes, you're in a castle all right,
but do you know the time?
是的，你的确是在一座城堡里，但你知道时间吗？
About four in the afternoon.
We haven't had breakfast yet, you know.
大约下午四点。我们连早饭还没吃呢，你看
Doesn't feed us much. Once a day if we're lucky.
很少给我们提供食物，运气好的话一天有一顿
Now, Professor, listen to me.
现在，教授，请听我说
This may come as a shock to you so steel yourself.
这可能会吓着你，所以做好心理准备
You have been brought back
to the early years of the Middle Ages.
你们被带回到了中世纪的早期
That's interesting.
这很有意思
I've always maintained that the Loop Theory of Time
我一直就觉得＜时间循环理论＞
shouldn't have been so arrogantly dismissed
by Crabshaw and his cronies.
不应该被 Crabshaw 那帮人轻易地否定了
Tell me about it some other time.
回头再讨论这个吧
We've got to get out of here before Linx comes back.
我们得在 Linx 回来之前逃离这个地方
Not yet, Doctor. This is the opportunity of a lifetime.
先别，博士，这可是一生中难得的机会啊
There's some most interesting work being done here.
这里还有很多非常有意思的成果
If only I could see it all properly.
最好我能把它们都研究明白
Professor, your life is in considerable danger.
I must insist you...
教授，你的性命处于相当大的危险之中，我坚持要你...
You go if you want to, Doctor. Go on, but leave me alone.
你要走就走吧，博士，不过不要管我
- Professor, don't you understand?
- Stop!
- 教授，你不明白吗？
- 停下！
- You are the one called the Doctor?
- You know who I am?
- 你就是那个叫做博士的？ - 你知道我是谁？
I have been expecting you. Why did you follow me to this time?
我一直在等着你呢，为什么跟我跟到这个时代来？
To prevent your interference with the affairs of Earth.
为了阻止你干涉地球事物
Don't you realise the harm that you'll cause?
你没有意识到你所造成的伤害吗？
This primitive planet and its affairs are of no importance.
这个原始星期的事情没什么重要的
That's a typically Sontaran attitude.
这是典型的桑塔人态度
Only one thing matters, to complete the repairs to my ship
我唯一在乎的事情，是完成我飞船的修理
and return to the glorious war that is my destiny.
返回到光荣的战斗中去，那才是我的归宿
Nothing must interfere with that, nothing and nobody.
没什么能干涉这个，没什么能，也没谁能
I vouch for her, my lord.
Without her help, I would not be here.
我为她担保，大人。没有她帮忙，我不能回到这里
She looks like one I would trust.
她看起来像是我能信任的人
Sit, child. Tell us where you're from.
坐下，孩子，告诉我们你从哪里来的
I can't. It's too difficult to explain.
我没法说，这太难解释了
The manner of her dress is strange,
and the manner of her speech.
她的穿着风格很奇怪，说话风格也是
There is much strange at Irongron's castle, Sir Edward.
Irongron 城堡里也有很多奇怪的事情，爱德华爵士
I told you of the knight that fights on
though it should be dead.
我跟你说过吧，那个骑士本来该死了，但还可以战斗
And one of the guards told me
there's a man from the stars that lives among them.
有个守卫还跟我说，有个从星星上来的人跟他们住在一起
A mighty wizard who makes magic weapons.
是个强大的巫师，会制造魔法武器
A man from the stars.
一个从星星来的人
I've heard it said he has the help of devils and magicians.
我听到过传言，说他得到了魔鬼和魔法师的帮助
- It is true, Sir Edward. I have seen it.
- Well, I know who's helping him.
- 这是真的，爱德华爵士，我看到过 - 对了，我知道谁在帮助他了
- It's the Doctor.
- The doctor?
- 是那个博士   - 博士？
Well, that's what he calls himself,
but he's no magician.
哦，他自己说自己叫这个。不过他不是魔法师
- Just some eccentric scientist.
- What does she say?
- 只是个心术不正的科学家 - 她说什么？
The words are strange, but I know her meaning.
用词有点奇怪，但我大概知道她的意思
Who is this doctor? What do you know of him?
这个博士是谁？对于他你都知道些什么？
Scientists, learned men.
科学家，学识渊博的人
They're being taken from the place I come from,
他们被劫持到了这里，从我来的那个地方
and I believe that the Doctor is bringing them here
而且我相信是博士把他们带过来的
and handing them over to Irongron.
把他们交给了 Irongron
What would Irongron want with these wizards?
Irongron 想要这些巫师干什么？
To make him magic weapons, my lady.
给他制造魔法武器，夫人
Irongron thinks only of war and conquest.
Irongron 脑子里只有战斗和征服
Anything that makes Irongron strong can work only to our harm.
任何能让 Irongron 强大的东西，都能给我们带来伤害
With an army of magic knights such as I fought,
就我斗过的那种魔法骑士，要是有了一整支军队
Irongron could conquer the whole kingdom.
Irongron 可以征服整个王国了
Who knows what other sorceries
he may soon have at his command?
谁知道还会有什么别的魔法师会听命于他
I'm sure the Doctor's the key to it all.
我相信博士是这一切的关键
He was there when one of the scientists was taken.
其中一个科学家被劫走的时候他就在现场
He has a machine that can travel through time.
他有一台可以穿越时间的机器
Well, it must be him, and somehow we've got to stop him.
嗯，肯定是他，我们得用个什么法子阻止他
If he's Irongron's ally,
如果他是 Irongron 的同伙
he sits safe within Irongron's walls.
There's nought we can do.
他稳稳地坐在 Irongron 的城墙内，我们拿他没办法
Oh, there's always something you can do.
It's just a matter of working out what.
噢，总是会有办法的，只是具体什么办法的问题
- A brave speech.
- She has the heart of a lion, sire.
- 这话很勇敢 - 她有一颗狮子一般的心，大人
I saw her give Irongron the sharp edge of her tongue.
我看见过他跟 Irongron 唇枪舌战
If I had an army of girls such as you,
I might hold this castle forever.
如果我有一队像你这样的女孩儿，我可能就可以永远守住这座城堡了
As it is, how can I fight Irongron and this doctor?
就目前来说，我怎么才能打得过 Irongron 和这个博士呢？
All right, I'll tell you how.
好吧，我来告诉你怎么弄
Now, the first thing we must do is grab the Doctor
现在，我们必须做的第一件事是抓住博士
and get him away from Irongron.
把他从 Irongron 那里弄走
And force him to make his magic for me? Aha, good thought.
然后强迫让他的魔法为我效力？啊哈，好想法
Aye, but how could it be done?
是啊，不过怎样才能搞定呢？
Oh, what's wrong with you?
All it needs is a sort of commando raid.
噢，你们怎么回事？只需要一个突击小队什么的就行了啊
You knock out the sentries, rush into the castle,
把哨兵敲晕，冲进城堡
grab the Doctor, and away.
抓住博士，然后走人
- You've got soldiers, haven't you?
- A handful.
- 你手头有士兵吧，有吗
- 有几个
- A raid? A bold plan.
- I'll go, Sir Edward.
- 一个小队？这计划很大胆
- 我去，爱德华爵士
You resisted well, Doctor.
你抵抗力不错，博士
I could have increased the power,
but I might have killed you.
我本可以加大功率的，但可能会杀死你
I need you alive.
我需要你活着
A brain of your capacity can be of use to me.
你这样容量的脑子对我来说很有用
Thank you.
谢谢你
You're not of this planet. How came you to be here?
你不是这个星球上的，怎么来到这里的？
Oh, I'm just a tourist. I like it here.
哦，我只是一个游客，我喜欢这里
- This hole in space?
- You haven't seen it at its best.
- 就这个破地方？ - 你没有见到它最好的一面
It has no military value, no strategic significance.
它没有军事价值，没有战略重要性
Once again, a Sontaran philosophy.
又一次，桑塔人的哲学
I'm Commander Linx, Fifth Sontaran Army Space Fleet.
我是军官 Linx，第五桑塔陆军太空舰队
Ah, yes. Yes, as I thought.
啊，是的是的，一如我所料
A Sontaran warrior.
一位桑塔战士
So, the perpetual war between the Sontarans and the Rutans
这么说，桑塔人和如坦人的持久战
- has spread to this tiny planet, has it?
- Emergency landing.
- 已经扩大到这个小星球了，是吗？
- 紧急降落而已
I was on a reconnaissance mission
when I was attacked
我在一次勘测任务中被袭击了
by a squadron of Rutan fighters.
对方是一中队的如坦战士
You have encountered my race before, Doctor?
你以前碰见过我的族人，博士？
Unfortunately.
很不幸，是的
I'll overlook that insult for the moment.
我暂且忽略你这种侮辱
- What is your native planet?
- Gallifrey. I am a Time Lord.
- 你的母星是哪个？ - 咖喱弗瑞，我是个时间领主
Ah, yes.
啊，是了
A race of great technical achievement,
一个有很高技术成就的种族
but lacking the morale to withstand a determined assault.
但缺乏士气, 无法承受坚决的攻击
- Oh, you think so?
- I'm only a lowly commander, Doctor.
- 哦，你这么想？ - 我只是个低层军官，博士
I merely quote from the appreciation
circulated by our military intelligence.
我只不过是引用我们军队情报部门散发的评价
Well, you'd be well advised
好吧，我倒是强烈建议你
never to put that appreciation to the test, Linx.
永远不会去验证那些评价，Linx
My only ambition at the moment is to return to my squadron.
在这一刻我唯一的夙愿，是返回我的中队
You can be of value to me. You can help repair this ship.
你对我来说是有价值的，可以帮忙维修飞船
You seem to have acquired some help already.
你似乎已经获得了一些帮助
Primitives. I adapted my ship's frequency modulator
很有限。我改造了飞船的频率调制器
and projected myself forward as far as I could.
尽力将我延时间线向前投射
Unfortunately, I only had the power
to reach the 20th century.
不幸的是，我的功率只够我到达20世纪
From which you stole the equipment
你从那里偷了这些设备
and the skilled help that you couldn't find here.
还有那些你从这里找不到的技术援助
Yes.
是的
But the work goes slowly.
但工作进展很慢
Commander Linx, if you will return
these people to their own time,
指挥官 Linx，如果你愿意将这些人送回他们原来的时间
I might possibly consider helping you.
我或许可以考虑帮你
Do not attempt to bargain with me, Doctor!
别试图和我讲条件，博士
Take that seat there by the controls.
去控制开关那边坐着
Move.
走
You're interfering with human evolution, Linx.
你在干涉人类进化史，Linx
Don't you realise the damage
that you're going to do to them?
你没有意识到你会对他们造成的伤害吗？
I have no interest in human evolution.
我对人类进化没有兴趣
I'm placing you under auto-control, Doctor,
我要将你放置于自动控制之下，博士
to ensure your complete cooperation.
以确保你会完全合作
Human beings must be allowed
to develop at their own pace.
人类必须要让他们以自己的步伐演进
At this period, they're just a few steps away from barbarism.
在这个阶段，他们刚刚脱离野蛮状态，还没走几步
You will monitor progress rates on
the input panel against the programmer.
你得在这个输入面板上监控程序员的进度
Now I must leave you in charge for a time.
现在我必须得让你自己负责一段时间了
You give them breech-loading guns now,
你现在就给他们致命的枪械
they'll have atomic weapons by the 17th century.
他们不到17世纪就会有原子武器了
They'll have the capability to destroy their own planet
然后他们就有了能摧毁他们星球的能力
before they're civilised enough to handle it!
但他们的文明还不能处理这类事情
You would do well to concentrate
on the task I have given you, Doctor.
你要是聚焦在我给你的任务上的话，还是能做好的，博士
Answer the programmer.
回应程序员
I still say this is no work for women.
我仍然认为这不是女人干的事情
I wouldn't have missed this for anything.
我不想错过这里任何一件事
Anyway, I'm the only one who knows
what the Doctor looks like.
不管怎么说，我是唯一知道博士长什么样子的
Come on, this way.
快来，这边
Ah, now these are more to my taste
than your iron man, Linx.
啊，比起铁人来这些更对我的口味，Linx
I will still perfect the fighting robot
for your army, Irongron.
我还在为你的军队完善战斗机器人，Irongron
We'll take these weapons to the men, Bloodaxe,
把这些武器散发下去，Bloodaxe
and I shall instruct them in their use.
我会教他们怎么使用
Rubeish! Professor, over here quickly.
Rubeish! 教授，快过来
Is that you, Doctor? I thought you were going.
是你吗，博士？我以为你已经走了
- A change of plan. I want your help.
- Are you wearing a hat?
- 计划有变，我需要你的帮助
- 你戴的是一顶帽子吗？
Behind me you'll find a panel. There's a switch on it.
在我身后你能找到一个面板，上面有个开关
It's dangerous, overheats the brain.
这很危险，可能烧坏你的脑子
- Panel... Oh, yes, I've got it.
- Right, turn the switch.
- 面板...噢，是有，我找到了  - 好，扳动开关
I've always thought that's why judges are so peculiar.
我一直在想为什么法官都如此特别
It's those wigs they wear.
原来是他们所戴的假发
No! No! That's the wrong... No, no, man!
不，错了！不是那个... 不，不，伙计
Sorry. I do wish I'd brought my glasses.
抱歉，我真期望我把眼镜也带过来了
Yes, so do I. It was the wrong one.
是，我也期望。刚才搞错了
Is this the one?
这个对了吗？
Yes, that was the one.
Thank you very much indeed, Professor.
是的，就是这个。真的非常谢谢你，教授
- Not at all, Smith.
- Smith. Yes, of course.
- 不用谢，史密斯 - 史密斯？是了，当然是
Will you excuse me? I've got to go and find a young girl.
我现告辞了，我必须得走了，得去找一个年轻女孩儿
I'll see you later, I hope.
回头再见，我期望
Young girl? I should've thought
he was a bit old for that sort of thing.
年轻女孩儿？我原本以为他有点太老了，不适合那类事情
Oh, well.
噢，好吧
Ah, good evening.
啊，晚上好
Get after him! Call the guards!
去追他！叫守卫！
(SHOUTING)
Catch him!
抓住他！
(SHOUTING)
Grab him! Grab him!
抓住他，抓住他！
(SHOUTING)
He who strikes Irongron dies!
敢犯我 Irongron 者死！
Doctor! Up here!
博士，上这儿来！
Thank you very much, Miss Smith. A most timely rescue.
非常感谢你，史密斯小姐，救援来得正是时候
This isn't a rescue, Doctor, it's a capture.
这不是救援，博士，这是抓捕
Let's get him out of here.
我们先带他离开这里
That fellow has the gall of a camel and the cunning of a fox!
那个家伙有着骆驼的胆汁，狐狸的狡猾!
You shall have your revenge, Captain.
He'll be with Sir Edward now.
你得要报这个仇，头儿，他现在去了爱德华爵士那里了
And not even a rat will come out of that castle alive tomorrow.
到了明天，就是一只耗子也别想活着从那个城堡里出来
By the stars, Bloodaxe, I swear I'll chop him up so fine
对着星星发誓，Bloodaxe，我会把他切碎
not even a sparrow will fill its beak at one peck!
碎得连麻雀都没法下嘴
One of my workers has disappeared.
我的一个工人不见了
Order a search of your castle.
下令搜索你的城堡吧
If you've lost one of your dumb, whey-faced ninnies, Linx,
如果你那些面色惨白的蠢人少了一个，Linx
then look for him yourself. My men are at rest.
你得自己去找。我的人正在休息
We march on Sir Edward within the hour.
我们一个小时内就要向爱德华爵士进军
I insist upon a search, Irongron.
The Doctor is of great value to me.
我坚持要求搜索，Irongron。博士对我价值非凡
And while he is at large, he could be dangerous.
而且如果他逍遥在外的话，就无比危险
The Doctor?
博士？
Bother me now, little toad,
and you will feel an axe in your skull!
这会儿烦我的话，小蟾蜍，小心我的斧头砍掉你的脑袋！
Master, I heard someone call ''Doctor''
while we were at that fellow's heels.
主人，我们在追那个家伙的时候，听到谁喊了一声“博士”
Is this Doctor a long shank rascal with a mighty nose?
这个博士是不是个长腿的家伙，有个大鼻子？
That is how he would appear in human eyes.
在人类眼中他应该是那样
Then he is no longer here.
那他现在已经不在这里了
Sir Edward sent raiders to my castle,
captured him.
爱德华爵士派了人到我的城堡来，把他抓走了
He has escaped!
他居然逃了！
- Tell Sir Edward we're back.
- Yes.
- 告诉爱德华爵士我们这就回去 - 遵命
- Now...
- You've been getting around, Sarah.
- 现在...  - 你还真是阴魂不散啊，莎拉
Are you on visiting terms with all the local nobility?
你跟这里所有本地贵族都有来往？
Doctor, let's get a few things straight, shall we?
博士，我们有话直说，好吗
Oh, dear. I'm afraid you're going to be awfully confused
哦，亲爱的，我担心你会非常困惑的
if you ask me to explain about the Tardis.
如果你想问我的是 TARDIS 是怎么回事的话
- The Tardis?
- Yes, my police box.
- TARDIS?  - 是的，我的警察电话亭
You were a stowaway, I imagine.
你是个偷渡客，我想
Yes, but we'll come to that later.
是的，但这个问题我们稍后再说
- Now then, why are you helping Irongron?
- My dear girl, I'm not helping him.
- 现在说说，你为什么要帮 Irongron？
- 亲爱的姑娘，我没在帮 Irongron
Linx is. I'm trying to stop him.
Linx才在帮，我一直想阻止他
SARAH: Linx?
Yes, perhaps you're lucky enough not to have met him yet.
是的，也许你是运气太好了，还没有碰到他
Nasty, brutish and short just about sums him up.
用几个词来总结的话，他是个险恶, 野蛮和短小的家伙
There was a strange-looking knight with Irongron.
Irongron 那里是有一个长相奇特的骑士
Yes, he'd have looked even stranger
if he hadn't been wearing space armour.
是的，如果他没有戴太空头盔的话，会看起来更奇怪
He comes from a planet
where the surface gravity is many times that of Earth.
他来的那个星球，重力是地球的好几倍
- A man from the stars?
- Mmm-hmm.
- 一个从星星上来的人？  - 嗯哼
- How do I know you're telling the truth?
- Because I never lie.
- 我怎么知道你说的是实话？ - 因为我从不撒谎
Well, hardly ever.
好吧，基本上从不
You ever heard of UNIT?
你听说过 UNIT 吗？
You work for UNIT?
你为 UNIT 工作？
In an advisory capacity, yes.
是的，以顾问的身份
They asked me to look into this question
of the missing scientists for them.
他们让我帮忙调查一下有科学家失踪的问题
But I thought you were responsible for that.
但我觉得你才是这事的黑手
My dear girl, I don't go round kidnapping scientists!
亲爱的姑娘，我不会去绑架科学家！
No, Linx brought them here to staff his workshop.
不，Linx 把他们带到这里来了，用作他工作间的工人
Now I've got to find a way of
sending them back to their own time.
现在我得找到一个方法，把他们送回自己的时间去
- This is the magician?
- Yes. This is the Doctor.
- 这位就是那个魔法师？ - 是的，他是博士
You have done well, Sarah.
你做得很好，莎拉
How do you do?
你好
It is a pleasure and a privilege
to be in the company of civilised people at last.
我很高兴，也很荣幸，终于见到文明人了
A courtly rogue.
这家伙还挺有礼貌
Is he willing to change his allegiance
and serve Sir Edward instead of Irongron?
他愿意改变效忠对象，从 Irongron 转向为爱德华爵士服务吗？
Well, he says he wasn't serving Irongron.
哦，他说他没在为 Irongron 服务
And there is another stranger at the castle,
someone called Linx.
在那个城堡里还有另外一个陌生人，叫 Linx
Yes, he's your enemy, I assure you,
not me.
是的，他才是你的敌人，我不是，我向你保证
We'd be well advised to join forces against him.
我倒非常建议我们连起手来对付他
- Does he speak truth?
- I'm not sure.
- 他说的是实情吗？  - 我不太确定
I suppose I could have been wrong.
我想我可能是搞错了
That's a generous admission.
那还算坦诚
Especially coming from one of the fair sex.
尤其是这话来自一位公平的性别(?)
Or he could just be changing sides to save his own skin.
也或者他是临阵倒戈，只是为了自己的小命
These wizards and warlocks were ever a treacherous breed.
巫师和术士从来都是奸诈的家伙
We'd best be wary of him.
我们最好小心他
I shall spare your life
我打算饶了你的命
if you cast your spells and incantations
to help me against Irongron, Doctor.
前提是你要帮我，用魔法与咒语对付 Irongron，博士
Refuse and you die.
如果拒绝你就死了
You offer a somewhat restricted choice, Sir Edward.
你给我的选择很有限啊，爱德华爵士
EDWARD: What is your answer?
你的答案是什么？
My services are at your disposal, sir.
我听候您的差遣，爵士
- Such as they are.
- Good.
- 跟他们一样  - 很好
Serve me straight, Doctor, and I shall reward you well.
为我服务，博士，我将给你很好的回报
Oh, master... Oh, but, master,
Irongron marches here before noon!
噢，主人...但是，主人，Irongron 的队伍午前就能到达这里！
We heard this said from his own mouth.
我们听到他亲口说的
Then we are lost. We cannot stand against them.
那我们就完了，我们没法跟他们对抗
- On the contrary, sir, I think we can.
- But how? With a handful of men?
- 恰恰相反，爵士，我觉得我们可以 - 怎么对抗？就这几个人？
Yes, sir, with just a few men I think
I can persuade Irongron that we have a full garrison.
是的，爵士，虽然只有几个人，我想我能让 Irongron 认为我们驻扎了大批人马
By the use of your magic?
凭着你的魔法？
By creating an illusion, anyway.
制造一个假象就行
Your magic will have to be powerful
indeed to discourage Irongron.
你的魔法必须的足够强大才能吓退 Irongron
It will be, sir.
会的，爵士
- The men are ready, Captain.
- Good.
- 人都就绪了，头儿   - 很好
Though for such an easy conquest as this,
即便是一趟如此容易的任务
'tis scarce worth strapping on armour!
穿戴上盔甲还是值得的
You and I alone, good Bloodaxe, could take that castle!
我的好 Bloodaxe，你跟我两个人，就可以拿下这座城堡！
Indeed we could, Captain.
我们还真可以，头儿
With Sir Edward's treasure I shall hire more men,
夺了爱德华爵士的财宝，我又可以招募更多人手了
and with Linx's weapons to arm them,
who shall stand against us?
再配备上 Linx 制造的武器，谁还敢跟我们做对？
When does the fighting start, Irongron?
战斗什么时候开始，Irongron?
In the time it takes to ride from here to Sir Edward's castle.
我们从这里出发去爱德华爵士的城堡，一到就开打
- Then I shall come with you.
- What, you?
- 那我跟你一起去   - 什么，你？
Ha! Bloodaxe, on my oath,
can you see that on a scaling ladder?
哈！Bloodaxe, 我得发誓，你可能看见这家伙站在攻城梯上面吗？
I have an interest in seeing the battle.
我有兴趣观看战斗过程
Those eyes have a thirst for blood.
那双眼睛很渴望见血啊
Well, find our bold warrior a horse, Bloodaxe.
好，给我们勇敢的战士找一匹马，Bloodaxe
Come, then!
那就来吧！
- Here's a few more for you, Doctor.
- Thank you, Sarah.
- 这里还给你找了一些，博士  - 谢谢你，莎拉
Lady Eleanor's got every serving wench
in the castle sewing away like mad.
Eleanor 夫人让城堡里面的所有侍女都在做缝制，跟疯了似的
I told you there'd be plenty of work
for everybody, didn't I?
我跟你说过每个人都有很多工作要做，对不？
Oh. Typically masculine arrangement, though.
噢，这安排就是典型的大男子主义
We do all the dirty work, you get all the fun.
所有脏活累活都我们干，你就乐趣独享
You don't think mixing this singularly noxious compound is fun, do you?
你不会认为搅拌这些罕见的有毒化合物是一种乐趣吧，是吗？
- How's the rest of it going?
- Not bad.
- 其它事情怎么样了？  - 不赖
I put Sir Edward in charge of painting the dummies' faces.
我让爱德华爵士负责画这些假人的脸
He's turned out to be quite an artist.
结果发现他还是个不错的艺术家
- Once I'd set him on the right lines.
- Excellent.
- 看来我还给他安排对了 - 非常好
- I'm glad I decided to let you stay.
- You decided?
- 我很高兴我当时决定让你留下来了 - 你决定的？
You know, I was never much of a hand
with a paint brush myself.
你知道吗，我几乎从来没有自己拿过画笔
- No?
- No.
- 没有？  - 没有
Nor a palette knife for that matter.
也没有拿过调色板刀
I'd like to study under one of the masters one day.
我想有一天我要到其中一个大师那里去学习去
Rembrandt, preferably.
伦勃朗，我比较偏好这个
- Rembrandt!
- Mmm-hmm.
- 伦勃朗！  - 嗯哼
Can you... Can you just go anywhere
you like in that Tardis?
你能...你能去任何你想去的地方吗，就坐你那个 TARDIS ？
Yes, within reason.
是的，只要有合适的理由
Then why are you staying here?
Why don't you go somewhere safer?
那为什么你要呆在这里？ 为什么你不去别的安全些的地方？
Because, my dear Sarah, I've got a job to do.
因为，亲爱的莎拉，我有工作要做
One that involves the whole future of your species.
其中一项跟你们这个物种的整体前途有关
Here, hold this will you?
拿住这里，可以吗？
- My species?
- Mmm-hmm.
- 我们这个物种？  - 嗯哼
You're talking as if you weren't human.
你说得好像你不是人似的
Well, the definition of the word ''humanity''
说起来呢，“人性”这个词的定义
was always rather a complex question, wasn't it?
一直都是一个挺复杂的问题，是吧
You know perfectly well what I mean.
Are you or aren't you?
你完全清楚我是什么意思，是还是不是？
If you mean am I a native of the planet Terra,
如果你问的是我是不是地球这个星球的原住民
the answer is no, I'm not.
答案是不，我不是
- Well, what are you, then?
- Me? I'm a Time Lord.
- 那，你是什么呢？  - 我？我是个时间领主
- A Time Lord?
- Yes, that's right.
- 一个时间领主？  - 是的，正是
And my people are very keen
to stamp out unlicensed time travel.
我的人民非常热衷于消灭未授权的时间旅行
You can look upon them as
galactic ticket inspectors if you like.
你可以把他们看作星际的检票员
- Galactic ticket inspectors?
- Mmm-hmm.
- 星际检票员？  - 嗯哼
I could murder a cup of tea. You're serious, aren't you?
我真想喝杯茶。你是说真的，是吗？
About what I do, yes. Not necessarily the way I do it.
对于我做什么，是真的。对于我做事的方法，则不一定
That's made them stop and think, anyway.
不管怎样，这使得他们停下来考虑考虑了
They've got guns!
他们有枪！
No man has fallen, Captain!
没有人掉下来，头儿！
- Your weapons do not work, Linx!
- You do not shoot them straight!
- 你的武器不管用，Linx  - 你都射偏了
Watch.
看着
- LINX: Those figures are dummies.
- Bah, your weapons are useless!
- 那些是假人
- 呸，你的武器一点用也没有
They do not move nor fall. They are not living men.
他们没移动也没掉下来，肯定不是活人
IRONGRON: I smell that fox of a Doctor behind this.
我闻到了博士那个狐狸的味道
Bring up the scaling ladders!
把攻城梯扛上来！
Here they come, Doctor!
他们攻来了，博士
(MEN YELLING)
Away! Away!
撤退！撤退！
Come on, move it!
快点，动起来
What was that stuff, Doctor? Some kind of gas?
那个是什么东西，博士？某种毒气吗？
Gas?
毒气？
Good heavens, what on earth do you take me for?
天啊，你把我当作什么人了？
No, it was some sort of superior stink bomb
不是，只是一种超级臭弹
with a few bangs and flashes thrown in for good measure.
混进去了一点儿能产生声音和闪光的东西
It's quite harmless, I assure you, but...
是相当无害的，我向你保证，不过...
(SNIFFING)
(MEN COUGHING)
Bring me wine! Wine, I say!
拿酒来！酒，我说了！
To quench the dust from my throat
and the stench from my nostrils.
冲冲我喉咙里的灰尘和鼻孔里的臭味
More, wench, more!
再来，丫头，再来！
Am I a sparrow to quench my thirst
with a few scant drops?
当我是只麻雀吗, 就几滴够解渴吗？
Ooh, mice!
噢，鼠辈！
A few loud noises, a few bad smells
and you scatter like sheep!
一点点响声，一点点臭味，你们就跟羊群一样逃散了！
It was sorcery, master.
那是魔法，主人
Black devil's work. You said so yourself.
黑魔鬼干的，你自己都说过
This wizard, the Doctor, he's gone and joined Sir Edward,
那个巫师，叫博士的那个，逃走后加入了爱德华爵士那边
and he threw all the fires and the stenches of hell itself at us!
是他朝我们扔那些冒烟冒恶臭的东西
With poltroons like these,
就你们这群懦夫，
it were ill work to lay siege to a hen coop!
就算围攻鸡舍都会一败涂地
They do but need food and rest to recover their spirits, Captain.
他们只是需要一些食物和休息，马上就能恢复士气了，头儿
We attack again tomorrow morning.
我们明早再次发起攻击
I will take Sir Edward's castle
我要拿下爱德华爵士的城堡
or I will see every man of you perish in the attempt!
要不然我要看到你们一个个都在攻城中战死
Chicken-hearted knaves!
胆小的鼠辈！
Begone from my sight!
从我面前消失！
Did I not see you yourself leading their retreat, Captain?
不是你带领他们撤退的吗，难道是我看错了，队长？
Taunt me not, little toad face.
不要奚落我，小蟾蜍脸
Or by the stars I'll see if the colour
of your blood is red like mortal man's.
要不然群星在上，我要看看你的血是不是跟凡人一样也是红的
You Earth creatures give up too easily.
你们地球生物太容易放弃了
I doubt if you have the potential
to make a truly military species.
我怀疑你们是不是有这个潜力，成为一个真正的军事种族
And you, Linx, you claim to like war.
还有你，Linx，你宣称你喜欢战争
- I haven't seen you doing much this day.
- I came only to observe.
- 今天我可没见你有什么作为  - 我去只是为了观察
I should have known better than
to look for interest in a struggle of primitives
我早应该知道, 不应该在原始人的斗争中寻找乐趣
Threaten me once more and I will destroy you.
再敢威胁我一次，我就毁了你
Why, you...
为什么，你...
Primitives! Childish, squabbling primitives!
原始人！孩子气, 只会哇哇乱叫的原始人!
It is well I do not need to spend much more time among you.
我不需要跟你们这里耗太多时间，那真是太好了
(ALL LAUGHING)
EDWARD: More wine, Doctor?
再来点酒吗，博士？
No, thank you, no. Oh, well, just perhaps a little.
不要了，谢谢，不了。噢，好吧，也许可以再来一点
Those knaves of Irongron's, they ran like rabbits!
Irongron 的那些混混，跑得跟兔子一样
Finest sight that ever I saw, Doctor.
And all thanks to you and your wizardry.
我见过的最漂亮的场景，博士。这都得感谢你和你的魔法
Well, we all played our part, Sir Edward.
哦，是大家群策群力，爱德华爵士
Now your magic works for us, our troubles are over.
现在有你的魔法为我们服务，我们的问题就结束了
No, not quite, I'm afraid.
不，还没完全结束，恐怕
The Doctor thinks Irongron's bound to attack again.
博士觉得 Irongron 还会再次攻击
And you shall affright the knaves with more of your sorceries.
那你再来几个魔法，把那些混混都吓退
It won't work indefinitely, I fear.
它不会一直有效，我担心
This time we had the element of surprise.
这次我们攻其不备
They won't be frightened off quite so easily again.
他们不会再那么容易被吓跑了
Then we've gained a respite. No more.
那我们赢得了一点喘息的机会。没别的了？
Actually, the Doctor does have another idea.
事实上，博士有另外一个主意
Then let us hear your counsel, Doctor.
So far you have served us well.
那我们来听听你的计策，博士。到目前为止，你为我们服务得很好
Well, there's one sure way to prevent Irongron
from capturing your castle.
有一个方法可以阻止 Irongron 夺取你的城堡
And that is?
这个方法是...？
You must capture his.
你必须夺取他的
(SCOFFS)
You advise the impossible, Doctor.
They outnumber us so greatly.
你的建议不现实，博士，他们人数远超过我们
My lady, are you familiar with these herbs and simples?
夫人，你熟悉这些草药和原料吗？
Ragwort, henbane, love-in-a-mist, fennel, sesame.
狗舌草, 天仙子, 黑种草, 茴香, 芝麻
Most we have dried in the kitchens.
The rest grow in the woods nearby.
大多数我们厨房里面有晒干的，其余的都生长在附近的树林里
Excellent. I want to brew up a little draught.
很好，我想酿造一点草药
You mean to mix a magic potion to slay the dog?
你的意思是混合一种神奇的药水来杀狗？
No, not quite. Just something
to calm him down a little.
不，不是那样。只是让他平静一点
I should have slain the filthy little toad there and then.
我应该当时就宰了那头肮脏的蟾蜍
I should have carved him up
into callops on the spot.
我应该当场打得他哭爹喊娘
Aye, master, it puzzles me
as to why you did not.
是啊，主人，我还奇怪为什么你没动手
Aye, well 'tis a matter of high policy, do you see?
这个，是个高级策略的问题，明白吗？
Above your understanding, hmm?
不是你能理解的，嗯？
As yet, we still need Linx's aid.
目前而言，我们还需要 Linx 的协助
Weapons he has promised me and by the stars,
weapons I shall have.
他答应给我的武器，星星在上，我要得到那些武器
Wonderful, magical weapons,
很不错的魔法武器
that will crumble the castles of those that oppose me into dust.
能把我对手的城堡轰成渣
And then, and only then,
shall Linx die by my hand!
到那时，也只有在那时，Linx 会死在我手上
Oh, 'tis a cunning plan, Captain.
哦, 这是一个狡猾的计划, 头儿
Aye, 'tis as well for you dolts that you have me to guide you.
是的, 有我来领导你们, 这对你们来说真是好啊
(CHUCKLES)
There's more to war than hard strokes, my good Bloodaxe.
除了硬碰硬，战争还有很多东西呢，我的好 Bloodaxe
Aye, master.
是，主人
Yours is indeed a towering intelligence.
你的智慧确实是高
Hold, Friar. What business have you here?
停下，修士，你们来这里干什么？
We come to beg alms of the good Captain Irongron.
我们来找 Irongron 队长请求一点施舍
The fame of his charity is spread far and wide.
他的慈善名声广为流传
You will find Captain Irongron in the great hall.
你可以在大厅找到 Irongron 队长
He is indeed a kindly and charitable man
他确实是个善良仁慈的人
and his temper is most sweet and pleasant.
而且他的脾气也很温和，令人愉快
Pass, Friar.
过去吧，修士
Heaven will reward you, my son. Come, brother.
老天会报答你们的，我的孩子。来吧，兄弟
(CHUCKLES)
'Tis to be hoped the two friars are fleet of foot,
看着吧，要么这两个修士就得仓皇逃走
or the church will have two new martyrs ere long.
要么教堂就得多两个殉道者了
(DOOR RATTLING)
What's that?
那是什么
That's a Sontaran spaceship, to be precise,
那是桑塔人的宇宙飞船，确切地说
and tremendously powerful for its size,
just like its owner.
从尺寸来看它非常强大，就跟他的主人一样
Here, give me your habit.
来，把你的外套给我
- What's wrong with him?
- Deep hypnosis.
- 他怎么了？ - 深度催眠
Ah, there you are, Doctor! Back again, eh?
啊，你在这儿啊，博士！又回来了？
- SARAH: Professor Rubeish!
- What?
- Rubeish 教授！  - 什么？
Oh, it's you!
哦，是你！
Doctor, I knew this girl was involved.
We should have reported her as I wanted.
博士，我知道这个女孩有份参与，我的意见是我们应该举报她
Yes, well, I'm very glad we didn't.
是的，不过我很高兴我们没有
In a few hours, that ship's going to be ready for takeoff.
再过几个小时，那艘飞船就可以起飞了
Yes, he's been working these people at a killing pace.
Come over here.
是的, 他一直在往死了用这些人。快过来这儿
Look.
看
No sleep. Practically no food.
They're starting to collapse like flies.
没有觉睡，基本没有食物。他们的身体开始崩溃了
I'm not surprised. He's suffering from near starvation.
我不觉得奇怪，他几乎要饿死了
We'll have to get them some food, Doctor,
or at least a drink.
我们必须得给他们找点食物，博士，至少得找点喝的
- There's no time for that.
- They'll die if we don't.
- 没时间干那个了 - 我们不管的话他们要死了
Sarah, listen to me.
莎拉，听我说
Linx's spaceship is just about ready for takeoff.
Linx 的飞船很快就要可以起飞了
And when that happens, there's going
to be the most tremendous explosion.
到那个时候，将会发生最强烈的爆炸
Everybody in this castle will die.
这个城堡里面的所有人都会死
These are the weapons I have promised you.
这些是我许诺给你的武器
Also a good supply of the projectiles that they use.
还有它们所需要的弹丸，很充足了
Oh, my thanks, good toad face... Good Linx.
噢，感谢，我的好蟾蜍脸...好 Linx
More weapons from the stars.
来自星星的更多武器
I shall complete the repairs of the improved fighting robot
那个改进过的战斗机器人，我会完成对它的修理
if I have time before I leave.
如果我离开之前还有时间的话
If you wish to leave, then you would do well to obey me.
如果你想要离开，那你最好服从我
Do you threaten me?
你是在威胁我？
I leave when I am ready, and that will be soon.
我准备好了就离开，很快了
And will you carry your starship on your back, good toad?
那你会把你的飞船背在后背吗，好蟾蜍？
You needed my knaves to bring it here,
you will need them to take it hence.
你需要我的喽罗把它拖过来，你也需要他们把它弄出去
Evidently you have no understanding
显然你并不了解
of the forces involved in interstellar travel.
星际旅行需要什么动力
I shall leave when I am ready.
我准备好了就会离开
It would be foolish of you to attempt to stop me.
你们试图阻止我的话，那就太蠢了
Doctor, what are you doing?
博士，你在干什么？
- Trying to break this hypnosis.
- It's very deep.
- 试着破解对他的催眠  - 程度很深
Narcoleptic condition, eh?
嗜睡症状，嗯？
The brain can still receive signals, Professor.
他大脑还可以接收信号，教授
Why can't you just send them as they are?
为什么不现在这样子送他们回去？
It's too risky with their minds in this state.
以他们的意识目前的状态来说，这样风险太大了
The transition might damage them permanently.
迁移过程可能会对他们造成永久损伤
I've never heard so much gobbledegook in me life.
我这辈子从来没听说过这样晦涩难懂的句子
But I expect you know what you're talking about.
但我还指望你能知道你在说什么
- Polka time!
- BOTH: What?
- 好戏来了！ - 什么？
It's the beat. Look, he's beginning to respond.
是节拍，看，他开始有回应了
Hide!
躲起来！
Up!
起来！
Get back to work!
回去工作！
Work! What's wrong with you?
工作！你怎么回事？
Get up or I will kill you!
起来，否则我杀了你！
- Leave him, Linx!
- Ah!
- 放开他，Linx！ - 啊！
How fortunate that you have returned, Doctor.
这么幸运，你回来啦，博士
My failure to destroy you
我没能干掉你
was the one thing that marred the pleasure
这件事让我很扫兴
of my approaching departure from this miserable planet.
眼看我就要离开这个悲惨的星球了
Don't you want to know why I've returned?
你不知道为什么我会回来吗？
It is of no interest to me.
我对这个没有兴趣
I came here to offer you my help.
我来这里是提供帮助的
We're sworn enemies, Doctor. Why should you help me?
我们是死敌，博士，为什么要帮我？
Because I want something from you.
因为我需要你提供点东西
If you will let me de-hypnotise people
and send them home
如果你让我解除这些人的催眠，把他们送回家
and help me capture Irongron and his men,
并且帮我抓住 Irongron 和他的人
then I will assist you in the repairs to your spaceship.
那我就帮助你维修飞船
Now, the weapons that you've made for Irongron
现在，你为 Irongron 造的这些武器
you can leave here in the castle.
你可以留在城堡里面
When it's empty, you can take off,
搬空之后，你就可以起飞了
destroying castle and weapons at the same time.
同时将城堡和武器一同销毁
All right, Commander Linx,
怎样，Linx 指挥官
what do you say?
你怎么说？
- You wish for my answer, Doctor?
- I do.
- 你期望我回答吗，博士  - 是的
Then here it is.
这就是了
SARAH: No!
不要！
The female, too. It seems I am doubly fortunate.
那个女性也来了，看来我是双重幸运了
- Get up. Get back to work!
- DOCTOR: Linx.
- 起来，回去工作！ - Linx
Can't you see that your prisoners
are physically exhausted?
你看不到你的囚徒身体都已经耗尽了吗？
They've had no sleep and nothing to eat for days.
他们好多天没睡眠没吃东西了
- They can still work!
- Not for much longer.
- 他们还能工作的！ - 不会太长了
LINX: I owe these primitives nothing.
我也不欠这些原始人什么
My only concern is to rejoin our glorious struggle for freedom.
我唯一关心的是重新加入我们争取自由的光荣斗争
DOCTOR: That's such an old tune.
那真是老调重弹
Don't you know there's no such thing
as the super race?
难道你不知道并没有超级种族这样的事吗？
Your Time Lord philosophy is egalitarian twaddle.
你们时间领主的哲学无非是平等主义那些废话
It is a weakness.
这是个弱点
Every species has its own weakness, Linx.
每个物种都有自己的弱点，Linx
For instance, you can only be stunned
by a blow on the probic vent,
举个例子, 只有对准你的通气口猛击，你才会被击晕
that small hole at the back of your neck.
那个通气口在你脖子后面的小洞那里
LINX: In our case, Doctor, it is a strength,
在我们看来，博士，这是种力量
because it means we must always face our enemies.
因为它意味着我们必须永远正面面对我们的敌人
Now, to return to the question of your demise.
现在，回到你的结局这个问题
I think it would be better
我认为最好
if you witnessed first the destruction
of your female companion.
你先目睹一下你女性同伴的灭亡
Well done, Rubeish.
干得好，Rubeish
- Doctor, are you all right?
- Yes.
- 博士，你还好吗？  - 是的
Yes. The blast was too brief.
还好，刚才的冲击波还太弱
But I wouldn't have been in a few moments.
但我也得缓一下才行
- Thank you very much, Sarah.
- Oh, pleasure.
- 非常谢谢你，莎拉  - 哦，乐意帮忙
Hadn't I better be getting on with the rest of your plan?
我是不是应该继续你的计划？
- Yes. All right, but be careful.
- You, too, Doctor.
- 是的，继续吧，不过要小心  - 你也是，博士
Right. Well, if we can secure our friend here,
好。嗯，如果我们能限制住这位朋友
we can get on with the job of restoring
his wretched victims.
我们还可以继续恢复这些可怜的受害者
Will this help?
这能帮上忙吗？
Rubeish, you're invaluable, my dear chap.
Rubeish, 你真是个无价之宝，亲爱的伙计
- Bloodaxe.
- Captain.
- Bloodaxe  - 头儿？
Fetch me Linx.
把 Linx 给我叫来
Fetch me that scabby-faced stoat from his burrow.
把那个面无表情的家伙从他的洞穴里弄出来
At once, Captain.
马上，头儿
Well, that should hold him for a while,
even on this planet.
好了，这样应该能困住他一阵了，即使是在这个星球上？
Why this planet?
为什么说“这个星球”？
Well, in his own environment, he weighs several tons.
哦，在他们的环境下，他重达好几吨
Fortunately, his muscles have been designed
for load bearing rather than leverage
幸运的是, 他的肌肉是为承重而设计的, 而不是力量(?)
Fascinating.
有意思
I'd always assumed that creatures
from a high-density planet
我一直以为来自高密度星球的生物
would have developed a pressure-balanced physiology.
会演化出压力平衡的生理机能
For example, if you take certain types of seaweed...
比如，如果你找几样海藻...
BLOODAXE: Linx! Linx!
-Linx?
-DOCTOR: Who speaks?
- Linx  - 谁在说话
Captain Irongron commands your presence.
Irongron 队长命令你过去
Tell him I'm busy.
告诉他我正忙
Well, come soon or we come and fetch you.
好吧, 快来, 否则我们来拎你
Who is Irongron? Is he a nice chap?
Irongron 是谁？ 是个好人吗？
Well, I wouldn't recommend him
for the Royal Society.
反正，我不会推荐他加入皇家学会
All right, Rubeish, you know how
to bring these people round?
好了，Rubeish，你知道怎么把这些人唤醒过来了吧
- Yes. A simple, repetitive optical...
- Yes, quite so.
- 是，很简单，一直进行光学的...
- 对，就这样
- I'll leave you to get on with it.
- What do you propose to do?
- 我就把这个事情留给你了
- 你打算干什么去？
I was going to preset this osmic projector.
我原本正要去调整好锇投射器
Send these people back to their own time.
好把这些人送回原来的时代
But now I have to find a way of stalling Irongron.
但现在我必须得找到一个方法拖住 Irongron
The robot! Yes, of course.
那个机器人！对了，当然
Thief!
小偷！
You common scullion, stand aside!
你，粗鄙的下人，站一边去！
How dare you obstruct me?
I shall have you flogged.
胆敢妨碍我？我会让人抽你的
Oh, so, a lady, are you?
哦，这么说，你是位小姐？
- A lady dressed as a serving wench?
- I'm hungry.
- 一位小姐穿得跟个侍女一样？
- 我饿了
Please let me go. I've tasted neither
bread nor meat for nearly a month.
请放我走吧，我已经快一个月没有吃过面包或白面了
No, nor done no work for longer
by the look of you.
看样子你也是很久没有劳动了
All right, my girl, I'll give you bread and cheese,
好吧，姑娘，我会给你面包和奶酪的
but you'll have to earn it.
但你要用劳动来换
Who are you?
你是谁
DOCTOR: I am a gift to Captain Irongron
我是送给 Irongron 队长的礼物
from the one who made me, my master, Commander Linx.
来自我的主人，指挥官Linx，是他创造了我
It is indeed the robot, Bloodaxe, though somewhat different in shape.
还真是那个机器人，Bloodaxe，虽然形状上有点不同
And I remember, Linx promised
to make me a second iron man,
而且我记得，Linx 承诺过给我再造一个机器人的
one that would obey my voice.
一个会服从我的语音命令的
But why has Linx sent you?
不过为什么 Linx 送你来？
Why has he not himself obeyed my summons?
为什么他自己不服从我的召见？
My master toils in his workshop to make you more fighting robots.
我的主人正在他的工作间里忙碌，给你造更多的战斗机器人
- He sent me as proof of his goodwill.
- What?
- 他派我来以证明他的善意   - 什么？
- Now I must return.
- Hold.
- 现在我必须回去了  - 停下
I would see something of the mettle of this gift.
我要看看这份礼物的品质如何
- Can you fight, iron man?
- That is my purpose.
- 你能战斗吗，铁人？  - 那是我存在的目的
Then fight me.
那来跟我打
I was programmed to fight for you,
not against you.
我被设计成为你战斗，而不是与你战斗
- Cease thy gabble and fight.
- You will damage my circuits.
- 少废话，开打！  - 你会毁坏我的电路的
Fight, iron man,
战斗吧，铁人
or you'll return to Linx in as
many pieces as did your brother.
要不就把你砍碎了送回 Linx 那里去，跟你兄弟一样
(SWORDS CLASHING)
What's that?
那是什么？
Oh, fighting again in the great hall, I'll warrant.
噢，又在大厅里打斗了，我敢肯定
Men were ever like children, fond of noise and brawling.
男人们就跟小鸡一样，就喜欢吵闹和打斗
Get about your work, girl.
操心你的活儿吧，姑娘
Hold!
停下！
Hold, I say!
停下，我说了！
We must slow this iron man's speed a little.
我们得让这个铁人的速度慢一点
Stick me some crossbow bolts in the creature.
用十字弓给这个家伙钉几下
We'll see if it fights as well with
a crossbow bolt or two in its gizzard.
我们倒要看看，肚子上中了一两箭之后它是不是还这么能打
And if that fails,
如果不行，
we'll lop off its head and try again then.
我们砍掉它的头再试
(MEN LAUGHING)
Isn't that a bit unsporting, old man?
那么做是不是有点不光明正大啊，老家伙
I mean, sitting ducks and all that.
我是说，打鸭子这样的搞法
This iron man talks like some Norman ninny.
这个铁人说话有点像某个诺曼底傻瓜
- Lift up your visor.
- I cannot reveal my face, Irongron.
- 抬起你的面具
- 我不能揭示我的面目，Irongron
Why?
为什么？
Because if I did, it might give you a seizure.
如果我那样做的话，你可能会被吓晕
- The wizard!
- Well, I did warn you, didn't I?
- 那个巫师！  - 怎样，我的确警告过你，对吧？
Seize him!
抓住他！
No.
不
The sword is too quick and clean a death for you.
这种死法对你来说太快太干净了
Look at that great spider!
看那里有个大蜘蛛！
(SCREAMS)
Now listen, all of you.
现在听着，你们所有人
You've been kidnapped, but you're about to be rescued, I hope.
你们被绑架了，现在要解救你们，我期望是
There's a machine here that'll send you home again.
这里有台机器是送你们回家的
Unfortunately, I don't know how to work it,
不幸的是，我不知道怎么操作它
and the chap who does has vanished.
而知道的人又消失了
But I expect he'll pop up again.
He usually does.
但我期待着他又冒出来，他经常这样
But the important thing is,
但重要的事情是
until then, you must carry on working
as if you were still hypnotised.
在那之前，你们要继续工作，假装你们还是在催眠状态下
- Can I ask...
- Morrison, don't start asking a lot of awkward questions
- 我能问问...  - Morrison, 先别问那些让我难堪的问题
I assure you, I don't know the answers any more than you do.
我先向你保证，对于答案，我知道得并不比例多
-IRONGRON: Linx!
Back to work, everyone. Someone's coming.
回去工作吧，所有人。有人来了
Linx, you dog!
Linx，你这条狗！
Where are you hiding?
你躲在哪儿？
Oh, there you are, you dragon-eyed toad.
喔，你在这里啊，你个大眼睛的蟾蜍
- Who put these bonds on you?
- The Doctor.
- 谁把你绑起来了  - 博士
I was struck from behind.
我被从后面袭击了
- Where is he?
- The Doctor is dying.
- 他在哪儿?  - 博士要没命了
What method have you chosen to destroy him?
你选择什么方法灭掉他？
Thank you, sir, for your charm and old world courtesy.
谢谢你, 先生，因为你的魅力和传统的礼貌
May I ask the purpose of this tomfoolery?
我能问问这些无聊的举动都是在干什么吗?
If you're going to have me shot,
why don't you get on with it?
如果你打算射杀我，为什么不直接来呢？
I would not have your death be in vain, good sorcerer.
我不会让你白死的, 我的好术士
I intend that it shall be of some use to me.
我觉得这我来说应该还有些用处
Nothing that I do will be of use to you, Irongron.
我做的任何事情对你都没有用处, Irongron
Oh, nay, Doctor, but you're wrong.
哦, 不, 博士, 你错了
These knaves of mine lack practice with their star weapons.
我的这帮喽罗对于这些星星武器还缺乏练习
A living target will give them a chance
一个活动的靶子, 是他们的好机会
to better their aim before tomorrow's battle.
可以在明天的战斗之前提高一点瞄准能力
You, shoot!
你, 开枪！
(IRONGRON LAUGHING)
These knaves of mine aim so ill, Doctor,
我这些喽罗瞄准能力是如此的烂, 博士
that you are mayhap safer to stand still.
也许你站着不动还安全一点
You, shoot!
你, 开枪！
The aim improves, Doctor. Be patient.
这次有进步, 博士．耐心点
We shall hit the target all in good time.
我们会在某个好时候击中目标的
I'm in no great hurry, I assure you.
我一点也不着急, 我向你担保
Oh, beshrew me, but I grow fond of this fellow.
哦, 该死, 不过我开始喜欢这个家伙了
Shoot when you please, lads, and a bag of gold
to the one that brings him down.
你们随意射击吧, 小伙子们, 把他射倒的人可以得到一袋金子
(GUNS FIRING)
By the stars! This fellow hops around
like a flea on a griddle.
星星在上！这家伙跳来跳去, 跟个跳蚤似的
Give me a weapon. I will destroy him.
给我一把武器, 我来消灭他
What? Would you spoil good sport, old toad?
什么? 要破坏我们的娱乐活动吗, 老蟾蜍？
(GUNS FIRING)
Doctor!
博士
Well done, Sarah. Come on.
做得好, 莎拉。快来
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(IRONGRON SHOUTING)
Sarah, wait.
莎拉, 等等
(DOCTOR WHISTLING)
Do you know, I think that was one of
the most active days that I've had in years.
你知道吗, 我觉得这是我在这几年之内运动最多的几天
Well, it's not as if I was a lad any more,
好吧, 我并不是一个小伙子了
once you're over 200.
尤其你已经过了 200 岁之后
So then, Doctor, your plans have miscarried, I fear.
看来, 博士, 你的计划被打乱了, 恐怕
- What will you do now?
- Oh, wait a bit.
- 你现在怎么办？  - 哦, 等一小会儿
Give the potion time to work and then go back.
给点时间让药水生效, 然后回去
- Doctor, you can't!
- Sarah, I must.
- 博士, 你不能！  - 莎拉, 我必须
Rubeish and all those scientists are there.
Rubeish 和那些科学家都还在那儿
Linx's spaceship is just about ready for takeoff,
Linx 的飞船也马上就要可以起飞了
and when that happens, there'll be a tremendous explosion.
到那个时候, 那里将有一场非常强烈的爆炸
All that will be left of that castle
will be a pile of stones.
那座城堡能剩下来的就只是一堆乱石
Irongron's castle is to be destroyed
by sorcery? Then all is well.
Irongron 的城堡会被毁于魔法？那就万事大吉了
There are innocent people in that castle, my lady,
那座城堡里面还有无辜的人, 夫人
and I don't like the idea of anybody going up in smoke.
而且我也不喜欢让任何人烟消云散
Not even Irongron.
即使是 Irongron
If you're going back, then I'm coming with you.
如果你打算回去, 那我跟你一起
I, too, will come with you if my master permits.
我也跟你去, 如果我的主人允许的话
Well, thank you. Thank you both.
好, 谢谢你, 谢谢你们俩
I can do with all the help I can get.
我可以用我能得到的一切帮助来做
Thank you, my friends. Your work is finished.
谢谢你, 我的朋友们, 你们的工作结束了
You may rest now for a time
until the power build-up is complete.
你们可以休息一会儿, 等能量聚集过程完成
Doctor, I think you'd better get a move on.
博士, 我觉得你最好赶紧行动
- Good evening.
- It's working, Doctor. Look.
- 晚上好  - 起作用了, 博士, 看
Aye, the villains sleep like innocent babes.
啊, 这些恶棍像无知的婴儿一样睡着了
Good.
很好
Well, we'll wait a bit to be on the safe side, then we'll go in.
好, 我们先在安全的地方等一会儿, 然后进去
At last, Doctor, there you are.
终于, 博士, 你来啦
Something most interesting happening here.
最有意思的一件事发生了
Yes, I see. Where's Linx?
是的, 我看到了．Linx 哪儿去了？
I don't know. He started his spaceship going then cleared off.
我不知道, 他启动了他的飞船就不见了
Where's the osmic projector?
It was over there on the table.
锇金属投射器在哪儿？之前是在那个桌子上的
He put everything back inside the ship.
他把所有东西放回飞船里面了
I'll just have to take it out again, won't I?
看来我必须得再去把它拿出来, 是吧？
Hal, scout around the castle.
Hal, 在城堡里四处巡查一下
See if Irongron and his men are sleeping.
看 Irongron 和他的人是不是在睡觉
If they are, disarm them and come back here.
如果是, 偷走他们的武器然后回来
What are you going to do, Doctor?
你打算怎么做, 博士？
Get the osmic projector.
Fortunately, it's an independent unit.
拿到锇金属投射器．幸运的是, 它是个独立器件
- Can't you switch this thing off?
- Well, I can try.
- 你能关掉这个吗？  - 嗯, 我可以试试
Suppose you don't succeed?
假如你不成功呢？
Then we've got between five and ten
minutes to get out of here
那我们就只有５到１０分钟的时候离开这里
before we're all blown to kingdom come.
否则就会被炸回老家了
(MAN SNORING)
- Couldn't you shut it down?
- No, the drive system is sealed.
- 你就不能关掉它吗？  - 不, 驱动系统被封住了
Linx must have taken the activator key.
I managed to get a hold of this, though.
Linx 肯定拿走了激活钥匙．不过, 我设法拿到了这个
I was lucky to get it out with the drive running.
很幸运, 引擎还在运行的时候我把它拿出来了
I think that should do it.
我觉得这个可行
I've got to send them back one at a time.
我可以每次送一个人回去
Get the first one to stand over there,
will you, Rubeish?
把第一个人拉到那里站着．行吗, Rubeish？
Come on, Morrison.
来吧, Morrison
All right, Rubeish, come over here.
I may want you to take over.
好了, Rubeish, 到这里来, 我想让你接手
Now then, all you have to do is this,
现在, 你只需要做这个
- this and this. Get it?
- Yeah.
- 再这个和这个, 明白了吗？   - 是
Right, here goes.
好, 走你
Right, that ought to surprise them
back at the research centre.
好了, 这应该会让研究中心的人大吃一惊了
- Next gentleman, please.
- Come on.
- 下一位绅士, 请过来  - 来吧
(ALL LAUGHING)
For the last time, Linx,
let there be no more talk of leaving.
最后一次跟你说, Linx, 不要再说什么离开的话了
And I tell you for the last time,
I am leaving now.
我也要最后一次跟你说, 我要走了
Our alliance is at an end.
我们的联盟到头了
It ends when I say it ends and not before.
我说到头了才能到头, 早了不行
You would be well advised to march
from this castle now and capture another.
强烈建议你们现在就从这个城堡出发, 另外再夺取一座
Soon you will have need of it.
很快你们就对它有需求了
- He threatens us, Captain.
- He does not understand our ways.
- 他在威胁我们, 头儿  - 他不懂我们的路子
Tomorrow, Linx, we smite the enemy, hip and thigh!
明天, Linx, 我们击杀敌人
But tonight, we feast.
但今晚, 我们先享乐一番
By your dawn, I shall be 700 million miles from here.
在你们黎明的时候, 我已经在7亿公里之外了
Can I be concerned with the fate of primitives?
我还会在意原始人的命运吗？
(ALL LAUGHING)
What did he mean, Captain?
他什么意思, 头儿？
He is a toad.
他是个蟾蜍
Who knows what a toad thinks?
谁知道一只蟾蜍在想什么？
Aye, Captain, 'tis truly said.
啊, 头儿, 这真是大实话
This stew has made me heavy.
这食物让我觉得头晕
Eh?
嗯?
That's Linx.
那是 Linx
Send the rest of them back.
I'll try and keep him busy.
把其他人送回去．我会尽量让他腾不出手来
(SNORING)
Trickery! Sorcery!
骗术！巫术！
- Now you, Professor.
- I really don't think
- 到你了, 教授  - 我还真不觉得
- I ought to go and leave you.
- Off you go now.
- 我应该先走, 把你留在这里  - 你感觉走吧
- Now then, this, this and this.
- Well, goodbye and good luck.
- 现在, 这个, 这个和这个  - 好, 再见, 祝你好运
It really was the most fascinating experience.
还真是最有意思的体验
I hope you and the Doctor will be all right.
See you back at research centre.
我期望你和博士都没事．在研究中心见
SARAH: Doctor!
博士
So...
这么说...
destroy my castle by sorcery, would you, toad face?
用魔法毁灭我的城堡, 你会吗, 蟾蜍脸？
Well, Irongron's magic is too strong for you!
好, Irongron 的魔法对你来说太强了！
Now listen, dog!
现在听着, 小狗！
In minutes now, this castle
will be destroyed by the sorcery.
几分钟之后, 这个城堡将会被魔法摧毁
If you'd save your miserable skins, then get you gone!
如果你还想挽救你们可悲的皮囊, 赶紧跑吧
Flee, dogs!
逃啊, 小狗们！
Flee for your life! Come on, waken, you dogs!
逃命去吧！快, 醒醒, 狗崽子们
And flee! Flee for your lives, you dogs!
逃吧, 逃命去吧, 狗崽子们
Waken! Waken up! Now flee!
醒醒！起来！赶紧逃吧
Doctor, do get up. We've got to get you out.
博士, 赶紧起来啊, 我们得把你弄出去
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
Something's gone wrong.
有事情不对了
He must have hit the takeoff button too soon.
他肯定提前按了起飞按钮
Come on, we've got about a minute
to get out of here. Quick! Run!
快点, 我们只有一分钟的时间跑出去．快, 跑！
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING BUILDS)
(BUZZING INTENSIFIES)
Well, you can tell Sir Edward
that his problems are over, Hal.
好了, 你可以告诉爱德华爵士, 他的问题都没有了, Hal
Irongron, his castle,
Irongron, 和他的城堡
his magic weapons and his sorcerer,
they're all destroyed.
他的魔法武器和他的术士, 他们都毁灭了
Will you not tell him yourself, Doctor?
你不亲自去告诉他吗, 博士？
He will reward you well. We owe you much.
他会重重奖赏你的, 我们欠你很多
I'm sorry. I'm afraid we must be off.
我很抱歉, 恐怕我们得走了
- Goodbye, Hal.
- Goodbye, Doctor.
- 再见, Hal  - 再见, 博士
- Goodbye.
- 再见   - 再见
You are truly a great magician, Doctor.
你真是一个伟大的魔法师, 博士
To tell you the truth, Hal, I'm not a magician at all.
跟你说实话, Hal, 我完全不是个魔法师
I'm not so sure about that.
我可不太确定
(WHOOSHING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)